<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
<!--appends===========================================================================================================================-->
  <append id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENLARGE_REDUCE">
    <supports> Druid </supports>
  </append>
  <!--broken-->
  <append id="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_BARBARIAN">
    <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Barbarian, Level 3)" number="1" supports="Skill,Barbarian" level="3" />
  </append>
  <append id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_HALFELF_STRENGTH">
    <supports> Lizardfolk </supports>
    <supports> Shifter </supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_HALFELF_DEXTERITY">
    <supports> Lizardfolk </supports>
    <supports> Shifter </supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_HALFELF_CONSTITUTION">
    <supports> Lizardfolk </supports>
    <supports> Shifter </supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_HALFELF_INTELLIGENCE">
    <supports> Lizardfolk </supports>
    <supports> Shifter </supports>
  </append>
  <append id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_HALFELF_WISDOM">
    <supports> Lizardfolk </supports>
    <supports> Shifter </supports>
  </append>
<!--feats===========================================================================================================================-->
  <element name="Shadow Touched" type="Feat" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HUNTER_HUNTERSEDITS_FEAT_SHADOW_TOUCHED">
		<description>
			<p>You learn how to bend shadows from your experience with the Shadowfell. You gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
				<li>You learn the invisibility spell and one 1st-level spell of your choice. The 1st-level spell must be from the illusion or necromancy school of magic. You can cast each of these spells without expending a spell slot. Once you cast either of these spells in this way, you can’t cast that spell in this way again until you finish a long rest. You can also cast these spells using spell slots you have of the appropriate level. The spells’ spellcasting ability is the ability increased by this feat.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast your chosen spells without expending a spell slot. You can also cast these spells using spell slots you have of the appropriate level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase, Shadow Touched" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INVISIBILITY" />
			<select type="Spell" name="1st-level Spell, Shadow Touched" supports="1,(Illusion||Necromancy)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
<!--items===========================================================================================================================-->
  <!--Circlet of Barbed Vision-->
  <element name="Circlet of Barbed Vision" type="Magic Item" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HUNTER_HH_HE_MAGIC_ITEM_CIRCLET_OF_BARBED_VISION">
		<description>
			<p>While wearing this circlet, the wearer's Charisma score decreases by 2. They also have advantage on initiative rolls. When making an attack roll, the wearer can use their reaction to gain a +5 bonus to the roll. They make this choice after they see the roll, but before the DM says whether the attack hits or misses. The wearer cannot use this ability again until they finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
    <!--broken-->
    <sheet alt="Barbed Vision">
			<description>You have advantage on initiative rolls. When making an attack roll, use your reaction to gain a +5 bonus to the roll.</description>
		</sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Plot</set>
		</setters>
    <rules>
      <stat name="charisma" value="-2" />
      <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_INITIATIVE_ADVANTAGE" />
    </rules>
	</element>
  <!--Jim's Missile Defense System-->
  <element name="Jim's Missile Defense System" type="Magic Item" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HUNTER_HH_HE_MAGIC_ITEM_JIMS_MISSILE_DEFENSE">
		<description>
			<p>As a bonus action, three (or however many are remaining for the day) twisting, whistling, hypoallergenic, gluten-free darts of magical force appear in a triangle floating behind your head. When an enemy gets within ten feet of you, you may target them with 1-3 missiles. Make a ranged spell attack for each missile. On a hit, the missile does 2d4 force damage. If the attack roll scores a critical, the missile does 5d4 force damage instead of the 4d4 force that you would normally get on a critical. If any of the attack roll is a natural one, all missiles turn around and hit the caster for 3 force damage per missile. Regains all missiles at dawn. Missiles can not trigger on your turn. Missiles only trigger when someone enters the radius, starting within the zone or teleporting in do not activate missiles.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Wondrous Items</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">0</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="0">0 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">head</set>
			<set name="type">Wondrous Item</set>
      <set name="attunement">true</set>
			<set name="rarity">Plot</set>
		</setters>
	</element>
  <!--Ondros Weapons-->
  <element name="Ondros' Clubs" type="Weapon" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_WEAPON_ONDROS_CLUBS">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_SIMPLE_MELEE, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_BLUDGEONING, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LIGHT, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_GROUP_CLUBS</supports>
		<description>
			<p> Ondros used to wield a quarterstaff on his travels. That staff is long since broken and now serves as these two clubs. Adorned with years of experience and use, these clubs have served Ondros well and could tell a lifetime worth of stories.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="sp">1</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="2">2 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="damage" type="bludgeoning">1d4</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_CLUB</set>
      <set name="stackable">true</set>
		</setters>
  </element>
  <element name="Ondros' Pistols" type="Weapon" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_WEAPON_ONDROS_PISTOLS">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_FIREARM, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_CATEGORY_MARTIAL_RANGED, ID_INTERNAL_DAMAGE_TYPE_PIERCING, ID_WOTC_DMG_WEAPON_PROPERTY_FIREARM_AMMUNITION, ID_INTERNAL_WEAPON_PROPERTY_LOADING</supports>
		<description>
      <p> Ondros has taken to collecting the pistols off of his notable enemies. Whether it was the novelty of the new technology or knowing that he doesn't know how to use them, Ondros seems driven to hoarding these metal contraptions.</p>
    </description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Weapons</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">250</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="3">3 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand</set>
			<set name="range">30/90</set>
			<set name="damage" type="piercing">1d10</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_WOTC_DMG_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_RENAISSANCE_FIREARMS_PISTOL</set>
      <set name="stackable">true</set>
			<!-- <set name="ammunition">ID_WOTC_DMG_ITEM_BULLET</set> -->
		</setters>
	</element>
  <element name="Ondros' Shield" type="Armor" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_GEAR_ONDROS_SHIELD">
		<supports>ID_INTERNAL_ARMOR_GROUP_SHIELD</supports>
		<description>
			<p>A shield is made from wood that has seen years of abuse. The gouges and dents in the wood have been filled in by magical vines over the years. Wielding a shield increases your Armor Class by 2. You can benefit from only one shield at a time.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="category">Armor</set>
			<set name="cost" currency="gp">10</set>
			<set name="weight" lb="6">6 lb.</set>
			<set name="slot">onehand,secondary</set>
			<set name="type">Shield</set>
			<set name="armor">Shield</set>
			<set name="armorClass">+2</set>
			<set name="proficiency">ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELD</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:shield" value="2" bonus="shield" />
		</rules>
	</element>
<!--spells===========================================================================================================================-->
  <!--Shadow Whip-->
  <element name="Shadow Whip" type="Spell" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_SPELL_SHADOW_WHIP">
      <supports>Druid, Artificer</supports>
      <description>
        <p>You create a long, shadow- like whip emanating from your right hand that lashes out at a creature in range. Make a melee spell attack against the target. If the attack hits, the creature takes 1d8 necrotic damage, and if the creature is Large or smaller, you pull the creature up to 10 feet closer to you.</p>
      </description>
      <setters>
        <set name="keywords"></set>
        <set name="level">0</set>
        <set name="school">Transmutation</set>
        <set name="time">1 action</set>
        <set name="duration">Instantaneous</set>
        <set name="range">30 feet</set>
        <set name="hasVerbalComponent">true</set>
        <set name="hasSomaticComponent">true</set>
        <set name="hasMaterialComponent">true</set>
        <set name="materialComponent">the stem of a plant with thorns</set>
        <set name="isConcentration">false</set>
        <set name="isRitual">false</set>
      </setters>
    </element>
<!--races===========================================================================================================================-->
  <!--shifter-->
  <element name="Shifter" type="Race" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACE_SHIFTER">
		<description>
			<p>Shifters are sometimes called the weretouched, as many believe they are the descendants of humans and lycanthropes. Whatever their origins, shifters have evolved into a unique race. They are humanoids with a bestial aspect; while they can’t fully change shape, they can temporarily enhance their animalistic features-a state they call shifting. Each shifter walks on the knife’s edge between the wilds and the world around them. Do they embrace their primal instincts or the path of civilization?</p>
			<h4>THE BEAST WITHIN</h4>
			<p>Early in childhood, a shifter forms a bond with a beast within, a totemic force that shapes their body and mind. Some shifters believe that these spirits are independent entities, and they may speak of Bear or Wolf as ancestors or guides. Most just see the beast within as a formidable expression of their inner nature, something that emerges as the shifter’s personality takes shape. The beast within is a pool of powerful instincts, and its influence is revealed by a shifter’s personality: a feline shifter may be cool and distant, driven by predatory instincts, while a shifter with a lupine spirit might be drawn to find and protect a pack. When a shifter fully embraces this beast within they physically transform for a short time.</p>
			<p class="indent">A shifter’s beast within is reflected by the shifter’s subrace. Four subraces are especially common:</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Beasthide</strong> often signifies the bear or boar: stoic, stubborn, and thick-skinned.</li>
				<li><strong>Longtooth</strong> shifters typically have lupine traits and prefer to run with a pack.</li>
				<li><strong>Swiftstride</strong> are often predatory and feline, but a swiftstride could also be a cunning rat who darts through the shadows.</li>
				<li><strong>Wildhunt</strong> shifters are born from any creature that tracks its prey.</li>
			</ul>
			<br/>
			<p class="indent">While the beast within certainly has a physical impact on a shifter, it has a spiritual and psychological effect, as well. Two beasthide shifters share the same special ability, but if one has the aspect of the boar and the other is more like a bear, they’ll be quite different in personality. With any shifter, identifying the beast within is a crucial part of understanding the character.</p>
			<h4>SIMILAR AND DIVERSE</h4>
			<p>Shifters are similar to humans in height and build but are typically more lithe and flexible. Their facial features have a bestial cast, often with large eyes, flat noses, and pointed ears; most shifters also have prominent canine teeth. They grow fur-like hair on nearly every part of their bodies.</p>
			<p class="indent">The traits of the beast within affect a shifter’s appearance as well. A swiftstride shifter may have catlike eyes and delicate build, while a beasthide shifter might be a massive brute built like a bear. While a shifter’s appearance might remind an onlooker of an animal, they remain clearly identifiable as shifters even when at their most feral.</p>
			<h4>THE JOURNEY YET TO COME</h4>
			<p>Shifters have a strong presence in the Eldeen Reaches but can be found in rural areas across Khorvaire, where they often live among humans. While they form powerful bonds to friends and kin, shifters place great value on self-reliance and freedom. It’s a shifter proverb to "always be prepared for the journey yet to come," and most shifters strive to be ready for change or opportunity.</p>
			<p class="indent">Shifters have a natural inclination toward classes with a primal connection. A shifter barbarian draws their rage from the beast within. A shifter ranger indulges their urge to wander and hunt. A shifter rogue harnesses their own predatory instincts. But shifters can pursue any path or faith.</p>
			<h4>SHIFTER NAMES</h4>
			<p>Shifters have no language of their own and often live in blended communities. Their names typically overlap with the names of other cultures in their region. Many shifters prefer to keep their personal names for their friends and use "wandering names" with strangers. These are usually tied to a physical or personality trait.</p>
			<p><strong>Shifter Names:</strong> Badger, Bear, Cat, Fang, Grace, Grim, Moon, Rain, Red, Scar, Stripe, Swift, Talon, Wolf</p>
			<h4>SHIFTER TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Your shifter character has the following traits.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Shifters are quick to mature both physically and emotionally, reaching young adulthood at age 10. They rarely live to be more than 70 years old.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Alignment.</em></strong> Shifters tend toward neutrality, being more focused on survival than concepts of good and evil. A love of personal freedom can drive shifters toward chaotic alignments.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong> Your size is Medium. To set your height and weight randomly, start with rolling a size modifier:</p>
			<p style="margin-left:10px;padding-bottom:10px;">Size modifier = 2d8<br/>Height = 5 feet + 6 inches + your size modifier in inches<br/>Weight in pounds = 90 + (2d4 x your size modifier)</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision.</em></strong> You have superior vision in dark and dim conditions. You can see in dim light within 60 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can’t discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Shifting.</em></strong> As a bonus action, you can assume a more bestial appearance. This transformation lasts for 1 minute, until you die, or until you revert to your normal appearance as a bonus action. When you shift, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 temporary hit point). You also gain additional benefits that depend on your shifter subrace, described below.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you shift, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em></strong> The beast within shapes each shifter physically and mentally. The four major subraces of shifter include: beasthide, longtooth, swiftstride, and wildhunt. Choose a subrace for your shifter.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="custom">Badger, Bear, Cat, Fang, Grace, Grim, Moon, Rain, Red, Scar, Stripe, Swift, Talon, Wolf</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{custom}}</set>
		</setters>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
      <select type="Racial Trait" name="Ability Score Increase, Shifter" supports="Shifter" number="3" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SHIFTER_SHIFTING" />
      <grant type="Language" id="ID_WOTC_ERLW_LANGUAGE_QUORI" />
      <select type="Language" name="Language, Shifter" number="2" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Shifter Subrace" supports="Shifter" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Shifting" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SHIFTER_SHIFTING">
		<description>
			<p>As a bonus action, you can assume a more bestial appearance. This transformation lasts for 1 minute, until you die, or until you revert to your normal appearance as a bonus action. When you shift, you gain temporary hit points equal to your level + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1 temporary hit point). You also gain additional benefits that depend on your shifter subrace, described below.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you shift, you can’t do so again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>You can assume a more bestial appearance for 1 minute, until you die, or until you revert to your normal appearance as a bonus action. When you shift, you gain {{shifting:temp hp}} temporary hit points.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="shifting:temp hp" value="level" />
			<stat name="shifting:temp hp" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Beasthide" type="Sub Race" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_SUB_RACE_SHIFTER_BEASTHIDE">
		<supports>Shifter</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Stoic and solid, a beasthide shifter draws strength and stability from the beast within. Beasthide shifters are typically tied to the bear or the boar, but this subrace could embody any creature known for its toughness.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Strength score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Natural Athlete.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Athletics skill.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Shifting Feature.</em></strong> Whenever you shift, you gain 1d6 additional temporary hit points. While shifted, you have a +1 bonus to your Armor Class.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Beasthide Shifter" display="false" />
		<rules>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_BEASTHIDE_NATURAL_ATHLETE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_BEASTHIDE_SHIFTING_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Natural Athlete" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_BEASTHIDE_NATURAL_ATHLETE">
		<description>
			<p>You have proficiency in the Athletics skill.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have proficiency in the Athletics skill.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Shifting Feature" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_BEASTHIDE_SHIFTING_FEATURE">
		<description>
			<p>Whenever you shift, you gain 1d6 additional temporary hit points. While shifted, you have a +1 bonus to your Armor Class.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Whenever you shift, you gain 1d6 additional temporary hit points. While shifted, you have a +1 bonus to your Armor Class.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Longtooth" type="Sub Race" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_SUB_RACE_SHIFTER_LONGTOOTH">
		<supports>Shifter</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Longtooth shifters are fierce and aggressive, but they form deep bonds with their friends. Many longtooth shifters have canine traits that become more pronounced as they shift, but they might instead draw on tigers, hyenas, or other predators.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength score increases by 2, and your Dexterity score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Fierce.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Shifting Feature.</em></strong> While shifted, you can use your elongated fangs to make an unarmed strike as a bonus action. If you hit with your fangs, you can deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Longtooth Shifter" display="false" />
		<rules>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_LONGTOOTH_FIERCE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_LONGTOOTH_SHIFTING_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fierce" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_LONGTOOTH_FIERCE">
		<description>
			<p>You have proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have proficiency in the Intimidation skill.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Shifting Feature" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_LONGTOOTH_SHIFTING_FEATURE">
		<description>
			<p>While shifted, you can use your elongated fangs to make an unarmed strike as a bonus action. If you hit with your fangs, you can deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>While shifted, you can use your elongated fangs to make an unarmed strike (1d6+{{strength:modifier}} piercing damage).</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Swiftstride" type="Sub Race" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_SUB_RACE_SHIFTER_SWIFTSTRIDE">
		<supports>Shifter</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Swiftstride shifters are graceful and quick. Typically feline in nature, swiftstride shifters are often aloof and difficult to pin down physically or socially.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Dexterity score increases by 2, and your Charisma score increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Graceful.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Acrobatics skill.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Shifting Feature.</em></strong> While shifted, your walking speed increases by 10 feet. Additionally, you can move up to 10 feet as a reaction when a creature ends its turn within 5 feet of you. This reactive movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Swiftstride Shifter" display="false" />
		<rules>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SWIFTSTRIDE_GRACEFUL" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SWIFTSTRIDE_SHIFTING_FEATURE" />
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SWIFTSTRIDE_SWIFT_STRIDE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Graceful" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SWIFTSTRIDE_GRACEFUL">
		<description>
			<p>You have proficiency in the Acrobatics skill.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have proficiency in the Acrobatics skill.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Swift Stride" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SWIFTSTRIDE_SWIFT_STRIDE">
		<description>
			<p>Your walking speed increases by 5 feet.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Your walking speed increases by 5 feet.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
      <stat name="innate speed" value="35" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Shifting Feature" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_SWIFTSTRIDE_SHIFTING_FEATURE">
		<description>
			<p>While shifted, your walking speed increases an additional 5 feet. Additionally, you can move up to 10 feet as a reaction when a creature ends its turn within 5 feet of you. This reactive movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While shifted, your walking speed increases an additional 5 feet. Additionally, you can move up to 10 feet as a reaction when a creature ends its turn within 5 feet of you. This reactive movement doesn’t provoke opportunity attacks.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Wildhunt" type="Sub Race" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_SUB_RACE_SHIFTER_WILDHUNT">
		<supports>Shifter</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Wildhunt shifters are sharp and insightful. Many are constantly alert, ever wary for possible threats. Others focus on their intuition, searching within. Wildhunt shifters are excellent hunters, and they also tend to become the spiritual leaders of shifter communities.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Wisdom score increases by 2, and your Dexterity increases by 1.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Natural Tracker.</em></strong> You have proficiency in the Survival skill.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Shifting Feature.</em></strong> While shifted, you have advantage on Wisdom checks, and no creature within 30 feet of you can make an attack roll with advantage against you, unless you’re incapacitated.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Wildhunt Shifter" display="false" />
		<rules>
      <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_WILDHUNT_NATURAL_TRACKER" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_WILDHUNT_SHIFTING_FEATURE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Natural Tracker" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_WILDHUNT_NATURAL_TRACKER">
		<description>
			<p>You have proficiency in the Survival skill.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You have proficiency in the Survival skill.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" />
		</rules>
	</element>
  <element name="Mark the Scent" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_WILDHUNT_MARK_THE_SCENT">
		<description>
			<p>As a bonus action, you can mark one creature you can see within 10 feet of you. Until the end of your next long rest, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make to find the marked creature, and you always know the location of that creature if it is within 60 feet of you. You can’t use this trait again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
    <sheet action="Bonus Action" usage="1/Short Rest">
			<description>As a bonus action, you can mark one creature you can see within 10 feet of you. Until the end of your next long rest, your proficiency bonus is doubled for any ability check you make to find the marked creature, and you always know the location of that creature if it is within 60 feet of you. You can’t use this trait again until you finish a short or long rest.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Shifting Feature" type="Racial Trait" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACIAL_TRAIT_WILDHUNT_SHIFTING_FEATURE">
		<description>
			<p>While shifted, you have advantage on Wisdom checks.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>While shifted, you have advantage on Wisdom checks.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
  <!--Lizardfolk-->
  <element name="Lizardfolk" type="Race" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_RACE_LIZARDFOLK">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">Only a fool looks at the lizardfolk and sees nothing more than scaly humanoids. Their physical shape notwithstanding, lizardfolk have more in common with iguanas or dragons than they do with humans, dwarves, or elves. Lizardfolk possess an alien and inscrutable mindset, their desires and thoughts driven by a different set of basic principles than those of warm-blooded creatures. Their dismal swamp homes might lie hundreds of miles from the nearest human settlement, but the gap between their way of thinking and that of the smooth-skins is far greater.</p>
			<p class="indent flavor">Despite their alien outlook, some lizardfolk make an effort to understand and, in their own manner, befriend people of other races. Such lizardfolk make faithful and skilled allies.</p>
			<h4>ALIEN MINDS</h4>
			<p>The lizardfolk's reptilian nature comes through not only in their appearance, but also in how they think and act. Lizardfolk experience a more limited emotional life than other humanoids. Like most reptiles, their feelings largely revolve around fear, aggression, and pleasure.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk experience most feelings as detached descriptions of creatures and situations. For example, humans confronted by an angry troll experience fear on a basic level. Their limbs shake, their thinking becomes panicked and jumbled, and they react by instinct. The emotion of fear takes hold and controls their actions. In contrast, lizardfolk see emotions as traits assigned to other creatures, objects, and situations. A lizardfolk doesn't think, "I'm scared." Instead, aggressive, stronger creatures register to the lizardfolk as fearsome beings to be avoided if possible. If such creatures attack, lizardfolk flee, fighting only if cornered. Lizardfolk aren't scared of a troll; instead, they understand that a troll is a fearsome, dangerous creature and react accordingly.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk never become angry in the way others do, but they act with aggression toward creatures that they could defeat in a fight and that can't be dealt with in some other manner. They are aggressive toward prey they want to eat, creatures that want to harm them, and so on.</p>
			<p class="indent">Pleasurable people and things make life easier for lizardfolk. Pleasurable things should be preserved and protected, sometimes at the cost of the lizardfolk's own safety. The most pleasurable creatures and things are ones that allow lizardfolk to assess more situations as benign rather than fearsome.</p>
			<h4>COLD AND CALCULATING</h4>
			<p>Most humanoids describe cold-blooded people as lacking in emotion and empathy. The same label serves as an apt depiction of lizardfolk.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lacking any internal emotional reactions, lizardfolk behave in a distant manner. They don't mourn fallen comrades or rage against their enemies. They simply observe and react as a situation warrants.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk lack meaningful emotional ties to the past. They assess situations based on their current and future utility and importance. Nowhere does this come through as strongly as when lizardfolk deal with the dead. To a lizardfolk, a comrade who dies becomes a potential source of food. That companion might have once been a warrior or hunter, but now the body is just freshly killed meat.</p>
			<p class="indent">A lizard folk who lives among other humanoids can, over time, learn to respect other creatures' emotions. The lizardfolk doesn't share those feelings, but instead assesses them in the same clinical manner. Yes, the fallen dwarf might be most useful as a meal, but hacking the body into steaks provokes aggression in the other humanoids and makes them less helpful in battle.</p>
			<h4>UTILITY AND SURVIVAL</h4>
			<p>The lizardfolk mindset might seem unnecessarily cruel, but it helps them survive in a hostile environment. The swamps they inhabit are filled with a staggering variety of threats. Lizardfolk focus on survival above all, without sentiment.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk assess everyone and everything in terms of utility. Art and beauty have little meaning for them. A sharp sword serves a useful and good purpose, while a dull sword is a dead weight without a whetstone.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk see little need to plan more than a season or so into the future. This approach allows them to maintain their current level of influence in the world, but it limits their growth. Lizardfolk have no interest in developing writing, making long-term plans, or cultivating other methods to progress beyond their simpie existence as hunters and gatherers.</p>
			<h4>HAPLESS SOFT ONES</h4>
			<p>At their core, lizardfolk view other humanoids with an indifference verging on pity. Born into the world lacking stout scales and sharp teeth, it's a wonder they have managed to survive for so long. The typical human would barely make it through a day in the swamps.</p>
			<p class="indent">Still, if other creatures prove useful to lizardfolk, those creatures can trigger a prote,ctive response made all the stronger by their apparent weakness. The lizardfolk assess such beings as hatchlings, young ones incapable of protecting themselves but who might prove useful in the future if they receive care.</p>
			<h4>LIZARDFOLK PERSONALITY</h4>
			<p>You can use the Lizardfolk Quirks table to determine a personality quirk for a lizardfolk character or to inspire a unique mannerism.</p>
			<h5>LIZARDFOLK QUIRKS</h5>
			<table>
			<thead>
				<tr><td>d8</td><td>Quirk</td></tr>
			</thead>
			<tr><td>1</td><td>You hate waste and see no reason not to scavenge fallen enemies. Fingers are tasty and portable!</td></tr>
			<tr><td>2</td><td>You sleep best while mostly submerged in water.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>3</td><td>Money is meaningless to you.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>4</td><td>You think there are only two species of humanoid: lizardfolk and meat.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>5</td><td>You have learned to laugh. You use this talent in response to all emotional situations, to better fit in with your comrades.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>6</td><td>You still don't understand how metaphors work. That doesn't stop you from using them at every opportunity.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>7</td><td>You appreciate the soft humanoids who realize they need chain mail and swords to match the gifts you were born with.</td></tr>
			<tr><td>8</td><td>You enjoy eating your food while it's still wriggling.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<h4>LIZARDFOLK NAMES</h4>
			<p>Lizardfolk take their names from the Draconic language. They use simple descriptives granted by the tribe based on an individual's notable deeds or actions. For example, Garurt translates as "axe," a name given to a lizardfolk warrior who defeated an orc and claimed his foe's weapon. A lizardfolk who likes to hide in a stand of reeds before ambushing an animal might be called Achuak, which means "green" to describe how she blends into the foliage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Lizardfolk make no distinction between male and female in their naming conventions. Each example name includes its translation in parenthesis.</p>
			<p>
			<b>Lizardfolk Names: </b>Achuak (green), Aryte (war), Baeshra (animal), Darastrix (dragon), Garurt (axe), Irhtos (secret), Jhank (hammer), Kepesk (storm), Kethend (gem), Korth (danger), Kosj (small), Kothar (demon), Litrix (armor), Mirik (song), Othokent (smart), Sauriv (eye), Throden (many), Thurkear (night), Usk (iron), Valignat (burn), Vargach (battle), Verthica (mountain), Vutha (black), Vyth (steel)
			</p>
			<h4>LIZARDFOLK TRAITS</h4>
			<p>Your lizardfolk character has the following racial traits.</p>
			<p>
			<span class="feature">Ability Score Increase.</span>Your Constitution score increases by 2, and your Wisdom score increases by 1.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Age.</span>Lizardfolk reach maturity arqund age 14 and rarely live longer than 60 years.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Alignment.</span>Most lizardfolk are neutral. They see the world as a place of predators and prey, where life and death are natural processes. They wish only to survive, and prefer to leave other creatures to their own devices.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Size.</span>Lizardfolk are a little bulkier and taller than humans, and their colorful frills make them appear even larger. Your size is Medium.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Speed.</span>Your base walking speed is 30 feet, and you have a swimming speed of 30 feet.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Bite.</span>Your fanged maw is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Cunning Artisan.</span>As part of a short rest, you can harvest bone and hide from a slain beast, construct, dragon, monstrosity, or plant creature of size Small or larger to create one of the following items: a shield, a club, a javelin, or 1d4 darts or blowgun needles. To use this trait, you need a blade, such as a dagger, or appropriate artisan's tools, such as leatherworker's tools.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Hold Breath.</span>You can hold your breath for up to 15 minutes at a time.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Hunter's Lore.</span>You gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Natural Armor.</span>You have tough, scaly skin. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use your natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield's benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Hungry Jaws.</span>In battle, you can throw yourself into a vicious feeding frenzy. As a bonus action, you can make a special attack with your bite. If the attack hits, it deals its normal damage, and you gain temporary hit points (minimum of 1) equal to your Constitution modifier, and you can't use this trait again until you finish a short or long rest.
			<br/>
			<span class="feature">Languages.</span>You can speak, read, and write Common and Draconic.
			<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<setters>
			<set name="names" type="custom">Achuak, Aryte, Baeshra, Darastrix, Garurt, Irhtos, Jhank, Kepesk, Kethend, Korth, Kosj, Kothar, Litrix, Mirik, Othokent, Sauriv, Throden, Thurkear, Usk, Valignat, Vargach, Verthica, Vutha, Vyth</set>
			<set name="names-format">{{custom}}</set>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d12">4'8"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="2d6">110 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<select type="Racial Trait" name="Ability Score Increase, Shifter" supports="Shifter" number="3" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="innate speed:swim" value="30" bonus="base"/>
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DRACONIC" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_BITE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_CUNNING_ARTISAN" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HOLD_BREATH" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HUNTERS_LORE" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_NATURAL_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HUNGRY_JAWS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bite" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_BITE">
		<description>
			<p>Your fanged maw is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. If you hit with it, you deal piercing damage equal to 1d6 + your Strength modifier, instead of the bludgeoning damage normal for an unarmed strike.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your fanged maw is a natural weapon, which you can use to make unarmed strikes. 1d6+{{lizardfolk bite:damage}} piercing damage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="lizardfolk bite:damage" value="strength:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Cunning Artisan" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_CUNNING_ARTISAN">
		<description>
			<p>As part of a short rest, you can harvest bone and hide from a slain beast, construct, dragon, monstrosity, or plant creature of size Small or larger to create one of the following items: a shield, a club, a javelin, or 1d4 darts or blowgun needles. To use this trait, you need a blade, such as a dagger, or appropriate artisan's tools, such as leatherworker's tools.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As part of a short rest, you can harvest bone and hide from a slain beast, construct, dragon, monstrosity, or plant creature.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Hold Breath" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HOLD_BREATH">
		<description>
			<p>You can hold your breath for up to 15 minutes at a time.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can hold your breath for up to 15 minutes at a time.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Hunter's Lore" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HUNTERS_LORE">
		<description>
			<p>You gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You gain proficiency with two of the following skills of your choice: Animal Handling, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Hunter's Lore" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ANIMALHANDLING|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_STEALTH|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" number="2" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Natural Armor" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_NATURAL_ARMOR">
		<description>
			<p>You have tough, scaly skin. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is 13 + your Dexterity modifier. You can use your natural armor to determine your AC if the armor you wear would leave you with a lower AC. A shield's benefits apply as normal while you use your natural armor.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have tough, scaly skin. When you aren't wearing armor, your AC is {{ac:natural armor lizardfolk}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="ac:natural armor lizardfolk:base" value="13" />
			<stat name="ac:natural armor lizardfolk:dexterity" value="dexterity:modifier" />
			<stat name="ac:natural armor lizardfolk" value="ac:natural armor lizardfolk:base" />
			<stat name="ac:natural armor lizardfolk" value="ac:natural armor lizardfolk:dexterity" />
			<stat name="ac:calculation" value="ac:natural armor lizardfolk" bonus="calculation" equipped="[armor:none]" alt="Natural Armor (Lizardfolk)" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Hungry Jaws" type="Racial Trait" source="Volo’s Guide to Monsters" id="ID_WOTC_VGTM_RACIAL_TRAIT_LIZARDFOLK_HUNGRY_JAWS">
		<description>
			<p>In battle, you can throw yourself into a vicious feeding frenzy. As a bonus action, you can make a special attack with your bite. If the attack hits, it deals its normal damage, and you gain temporary hit points (minimum of 1) equal to your Constitution modifier, and you can't use this trait again until you finish a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>As a bonus action, you can make a special attack with your bite. If the attack hits, it deals its normal damage, and you gain {{hungry jaws:hp:temp}} temporary hit points. 1/ short rest.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="hungry jaws:hp:temp" value="1" bonus="hungry jaws" />
			<stat name="hungry jaws:hp:temp" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="hungry jaws" />
		</rules>
	</element>
<!--backgrounds===========================================================================================================================-->
  <!--Druid of Ravnica-->
  <element name="Druid of Ravnica" type="Background" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_BACKGROUND_DRUID_OF_RAVNICA">
  		<description>
  			<p>A Loxodon druid from the eastern savannahs of Rodethan, Ondros the Healer studies the druidic ideals of love and respect for nature. After learning all he could from his home tribe, he set off on a pilgrimage in search of the fabled druidic circle of the shepherd. Ondros spent one last night with his wife, Rena, before he departed and promised to return to her following the completion of his training. During his travels he stumbled upon the Rubicon Corporation trying to establish a loggin camp on a sacred and ancient grove. Ondros sabotaged the loggers equipment and quickly fled feeling good about saving the grove. He quickly realized that Rubicon had put a hit out on him, and that he was being hunted by mercenaries. Through luck and sheer force of will, Ondros was able to make it to the Kingdom of Kariellum. With mercenaries quick on his tail, he was forced to forgo an immediate trip to the druidic circle and sought refuge in the dwarven/gnome city of Twincrown. Unfortunately, while posing as a horse in front of a tavern, they were discovered. The hired thugs attacked, and all seemed lost. With a merry tune and an angelic voice, a halfling bard named Wayne stepped in to help. The two couldn't defeat all the mercenaries, but managed to bartered for their lives. They were thrown into an indentured servitude camp, deep below Twincrown. Over the next three months they became close with a pirate who organized an escape plan with the two. Finally free, Ondros and Wayne fled to Chinook fearing the Rubicon Corporation. Now they find themselves in Rigmoore thanks to an unusual sign you received from the Wildmother.</p>
  			<ul class="unstyled">
  				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Athletics, Intimidation</li>
  				<li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> One type of gaming set</li>
  				<li><strong>Languages:</strong> Choose one of Celestial, Draconic, Goblin, or Minotaur</li>
  				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> Your wits and whatever you were able to hold onto between shipwrecks.</li>
  			</ul>
  			<div element="ID_HH_HE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DRUID_OF_RAVNICA_PYROMANIAC" />
  			<div element="ID_HH_HE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DRUID_OF_RAVNICA_PYROMANIAC_SPELLS" />
  			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
  			<p> Coming from a land of peace, where nature reigns, never forget your connection to home.</p>
  		</description>
  		<setters>
  			<set name="short">Athletics, Intimidation, Language</set>
  		</setters>
  		<rules>
  			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS" />
  			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INTIMIDATION" />
  			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency, Druid of Ravnica" supports="Gaming Set" />
  			<select type="Language" name="Language, Druid of Ravnica" supports="ID_LANGUAGE_CELESTIAL|ID_LANGUAGE_DRACONIC|ID_LANGUAGE_GOBLIN|ID_GGTR_LANGUAGE_MINOTAUR" />
  			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_HH_HE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DRUID_OF_RAVNICA_PYROMANIAC" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_OPTIONAL_BACKGROUND_FEATURE"/>
  			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_HH_HE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DRUID_OF_RAVNICA_PYROMANIAC_SPELLS" />
  			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List" number="1">
  				<item id="1">Your love for nature and its versatility inspires you to find new uses for its materials, you love scavenging natural materials for your crafts.</item>
  				<item id="2">...</item>
  				<item id="3">...</item>
  				<item id="4">...</item>
  				<item id="5">...</item>
  				<item id="6">...</item>
  				<item id="7">...</item>
  				<item id="8">...</item>
  			</select>
  			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
  				<item id="1">I must protect what I care about, but life on the run has made me wary for my own survival. (Chaotic) </item>
  				<item id="2">...</item>
  				<item id="3">...</item>
  				<item id="4">...</item>
  				<item id="5">...</item>
  				<item id="6">...</item>
  			</select>
  			<select name="Bond" type="List">
  				<item id="1">The last few years have felt like several lifetimes, I have become accustomed to loosing friends.</item>
  				<item id="2">...</item>
  				<item id="3">...</item>
  				<item id="4">...</item>
  				<item id="5">...</item>
  				<item id="6">...</item>
  			</select>
  			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
  				<item id="1">My time on the run has made me forget about the past.</item>
  				<item id="2">...</item>
  				<item id="3">...</item>
  				<item id="4">...</item>
  				<item id="5">...</item>
  				<item id="6">...</item>
  			</select>
  		</rules>
  	</element>
  	<element name="Feature: Pyromaniac" type="Background Feature" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DRUID_OF_RAVNICA_PYROMANIAC">
  		<supports>Background Feature, Primary</supports>
  		<description>
  			<p>You have long enjoyed the power and curiosity of flame. Acting both predictibly and erratic the nature of flame has always loomed in the back of your mind. Over many years your have sought to learn more about the primordial nature of fire itself granting you limited number of extra fire spells to your available spell list.</p>
  		</description>
  		<sheet alt="Pyromaniac">
  			<description>You have long enjoyed the power and curiosity of flame. Acting both predictibly and erratic the nature of flame has always loomed in the back of your mind. Over many years your have sought to learn more about the primordial nature of fire itself granting you limited number of extra fire spells to your available spell list.</description>
  		</sheet>
  	</element>
  	<element name="Pyromaniac Spells" type="Background Feature" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DRUID_OF_RAVNICA_PYROMANIAC_SPELLS">
  		<description>
  			<p><em>Prerequisite: Spellcasting or Pact Magic class feature</em></p>
  			<p>For you, the spells on the Pyromaniac Spells table are added to the spell list of your spellcasting class. (If you are a multiclass character with multiple spell lists, these spells are added to all of them.)</p>
  			<h5>Boros Guild Spells</h5>
  			<table>
  				<thead>
  					<tr><td>Spell Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
  				</thead>
  				<tr><td>Cantrip</td><td><em>fire bolt, sacred flame</em></td></tr>
  				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>guiding bolt, heroism</em></td></tr>
  				<tr><td>2nd</td><td><em>aid, scorching ray</em></td></tr>
  				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>beacon of hope, blinding smite</em></td></tr>
  				<tr><td>4th</td><td><em>death ward, wall of fire</em></td></tr>
  				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>flame strike</em></td></tr>
  			</table>
  			<p class="indent">Your magic often features dramatic bursts of flame or radiance. When you cast beneficial spells on your allies, they appear momentarily surrounded with halos of bright fire.</p>
  		</description>
  		<sheet>
  			<description>Your magic often features dramatic bursts of flame or radiance. When you cast beneficial spells on your allies, they appear momentarily surrounded with halos of bright fire.</description>
  		</sheet>
  		<spellcasting all="true" extend="true">
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_BOLT</extend>
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SACRED_FLAME</extend>
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT</extend>
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM</extend>
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_AID</extend>
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY</extend>
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BEACON_OF_HOPE</extend>
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDING_SMITE</extend>
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD</extend>
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE</extend>
  			<extend>ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE</extend>
  		</spellcasting>
  	</element>
<!--subclasses===========================================================================================================================-->
    <element name="Path of the Beast" type="Archetype" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_PATH_OF_THE_BEAST">
		<supports>Primal Path</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Barbarians who walk the Path of Beast draw their rage from a bestial spark burning within their souls. That beast howls to be released and bursts forth in the throes of rage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Those who tread this path might be inhabited by a primal spirit or descended from shapeshifters. You can choose the origin of your feral might or determine it randomly by rolling on the Origin of the Beast table.</p>
			<h5 class="caption">ORIGIN OF THE BEAST</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td class="col-10">d4</td><td>Origin</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1</td><td>One of your parents is a lycanthrope, and you’ve inherited some of the curse.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>2</td><td>You are descended from a legendary druid, a fact manifested by your ability to partially change shape.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>3</td><td>A fey spirit gifted you with the ability to adopt different bestial aspects.</td></tr>
				<tr><td>4</td><td>An ancient animal spirit dwells within you, allowing you to walk this path.</td></tr>
			</table>
			<div element="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_FORM_OF_THE_BEAST" />
			<div element="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_BESTIAL_SOUL" />
			<div element="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_INFECTIOUS_FURY" />
			<div element="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_CALL_THE_HUNT" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You draw their rage from a bestial spark burning within their souls.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_FORM_OF_THE_BEAST" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_BESTIAL_SOUL" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_INFECTIOUS_FURY" level="10" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_CALL_THE_HUNT" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Form of the Beast" type="Archetype Feature" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_FORM_OF_THE_BEAST">
		<description>
			<p><em>3rd-level Path of the Beast feature</em></p>
			<p>Starting when you choose this path at 3rd level, when you enter your rage, you can transform, revealing the bestial power within you. Until the rage ends, you manifest a natural weapon. It counts as a simple melee weapon for you, and you add your Strength modifier to the attack and damage rolls when you attack with it, as normal. You choose the weapon’s form each time you rage:</p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Bite.</strong> Your mouth transforms into a bestial muzzle or great mandibles (your choice). It deals 1d8 piercing damage on a hit. Once on each of your turns when you damage a creature with this bite, you regain a number of hit points equal to your proficiency bonus, provided you have less than half your hit points when you hit.</li>
				<li><strong>Claws.</strong> Each of your hands transforms into a claw, which you can use as a weapon if it’s empty. It deals 1d6 slashing damage on a hit. Once on each of your turns when you attack with a claw using the Attack action, you can make one additional claw attack as part of the same action.</li>
				<li><strong>Tail.</strong> You grow a lashing, spiny tail, which deals 1d8 piercing damage on a hit and has the reach property. If a creature you can see within 10 feet of you hits you with an attack roll, you can use your reaction to swipe your tail and roll a d8, applying a bonus to your AC equal to the number rolled, potentially causing the attack to miss you.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you enter your rage, you can transform. Until the rage ends, you manifest a natural weapon. It counts as a simple melee weapon for you, and you add your Strength modifier to the attack and damage rolls when you attack with it, as normal. You manifest a natural melee weapon each time you rage:
			Bite. Your bite deals 1d8 piercing damage on a hit. Once on each of your turns when you damage a creature with your bite, you regain {{proficiency}} hp, if you are at half health or lower.
			Claws. Your claws deal 1d6 slashing damage on a hit. When you take the Attack action on your turn and make an attack with your claws, you can make one additional attack using your claws as part of the same action.
			Tail. Your tail deals 1d8 piercing damage on a hit and has the reach property. If a creature you can see within 10 feet of you hits you with an attack roll, you can use your reaction to swipe your tail and roll a d8, applying a bonus to your AC equal to the number rolled, potentially causing the attack to miss you.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="form of the beast:hp" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="form of the beast:hp" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bestial Soul" type="Archetype Feature" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_BESTIAL_SOUL">
		<description>
			<p><em>6th-level Path of the Beast feature</em></p>
			<p>The feral spirit within you grows in power, causing the natural weapons of your Form of the Beast to count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can also call on the feral spirit to help you adapt to your surroundings. When you finish a short or long rest, choose one of the following benefits, which lasts until you finish a short or long rest:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>You gain a swimming speed equal to your walking speed, and you can breathe underwater.</li>
				<li>You gain a climbing speed equal to your walking speed, and you can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.</li>
				<li>When you jump, you can make a Strength (Athletics) check and extend your jump by a number of feet equal to the check’s total. You can make this special check only once per turn.</li>
			</ul>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Natural weapons of your Form of the Beast to count as magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.
			When you finish a short or long rest, choose one of the following benefits, which lasts until you finish a short or long rest:
			You gain a swimming speed of {{speed}}ft, and you can breathe underwater.
			You gain a climbing speed of {{speed}}ft, and you can climb difficult surfaces, including upside down on ceilings, without needing to make an ability check.
			When you jump, you can make a Athletics check and extend your jump by a number of feet equal to the check’s total. You can make this special check only once per turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Infectious Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_INFECTIOUS_FURY">
		<description>
			<p><em>10th-level Path of the Beast feature</em></p>
			<p>When you hit a creature with your natural weapons while you are raging, the spirit within you can curse your target with rabid fury. The target must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your Constitution modifier + your proficiency bonus) or suffer one of the following effects (your choice):</p>
			<ul>
				<li>The target must use its reaction to make a melee attack against another creature of your choice that you can see.</li>
				<li>Target takes 2d12 psychic damage.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{infectious fury:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description>When you hit a creature with your natural weapons while you are raging, the spirit within you can curse your target with rabid fury. The target must succeed on a DC {{infectious fury:dc}} Wisdom save or suffer one of the following effects:
			The target must use its reaction to make a melee attack against another creature of your choice that you can see.
			Target takes 2d12 psychic damage.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="infectious fury:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="infectious fury:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="infectious fury:dc" value="constitution:modifier" />
			<stat name="infectious fury:usage" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="infectious fury:usage" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Call the Hunt" type="Archetype Feature" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_HH_HE_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_BEAST_CALL_THE_HUNT">
		<description>
			<p><em>14th-level Path of the Beast feature</em></p>
			<p>The beast within grows so powerful that you can spread its ferocity to your allies. When you enter your rage, you can choose a number of willing creatures you can see within 30 feet of you equal to your Constitution modifier (minimum of one creature). Until your rage ends, the chosen creatures gain the Reckless Attack feature and you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened. You also gain 5 temporary hit points for each creature that accepts the benefit.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your Constitution modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="{{call the hunt:usage}}/Long Rest">
			<description>When you enter your rage, you can choose {{call the hunt:creatures}} willing creatures you can see within 30 feet of you. Until your rage ends, the chosen creatures gain the Reckless Attack feature and you have advantage on saving throws against being frightened. You also gain 5 temporary hit points for each creature that accepts the benefit.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="call the hunt:creatures" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="call the hunt:creatures" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="call the hunt:usage" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="call the hunt:usage" value="constitution:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
<!--classes===========================================================================================================================-->
	<info>
        <name>Blood Hunter</name>
        <description>The Blood Hunter class (v2.0).</description>
        <author url="http://www.dmsguild.com/product/170777/Blood-Hunter-Class">Matthew Mercer</author>
        <update version="0.1.9">
            <file name="class-bloodhunter.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/third-party/critical-role/classes/class-bloodhunter.xml" />
        </update>
    </info>
    <element name="Blood Hunter" type="Class" source="hunters-edits" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER">
        <description>
            <p>In a landscape tormented by all manner of beasts, devils, and abominations from beyond the veil, most live in fear of the dark, of superstition, and of the unknown. Some grow hardened by this experience, instead choosing to stand up and fight against the tide of shadow. These folk are called ‘heroes’.</p>
            <p class="indent">Some, however, are so fanatical and bent on destroying the anethema that plagues the countryside that they embrace dark, forbidden knowledge. They sacrifice some of their own vital force in dubious, forgotten blood rituals to better understand their enemies. Their methods sometimes blur the line between themselves and the evils they hunt, calling their own humanity into question.</p>
            <p class="indent">These folk are called ‘Blood Hunters’.</p>
            <h4>BECOME THE ENEMY TO UNDERSTAND THE ENEMY</h4>
            <p>These warriors have chosen to merge the martial pursuit of deadly weapon paly with elements of vicious blood magic to create impressively effective combat techniques. They surrender their own vitality to form a bond with their weapon, allowing them to harness the elements in a whirlwind of dangerous strikes. Their deep knowledge and unnatural connection with wicked creatures allows them an advantage in tracking, hunting, and destroying even the most resilient of abhorrent fiends. By mastering control over their own lifeblood and the lifeblood of others, they gain insight into their foes and the ability to manipulate them from the inside. Some brew crude, poisonous alchemical tonics from the harvested organs of felled monsters, mutating their blood and bodies to be even further in tune with their quarry, becoming something other than human themselves. Others go further, reaching out and making a pact with lesser dark entities in hopes of using their grim gifts against greaters evils. Many blood hunters push too far for their goals, falling to their own hubris and becoming the monsters they’ve chosen to hunt. This is the greatest feat of a blood hunter, and of the societies at large that shun them.</p>
            <h4>ALMOST AS FEARED AS THEIR PREY</h4>
            <p>The nature of their abilities and training has bred many rumors across the lands, some of which aren’t too far from the truth. Common folk consider them cursed, often turning them away at the door. Nobles see them as occasionally convenient, but a generally reviled nuisance. Mages find them useful allies if kept at arm’s length, while pious clerics and paladins keep their distance with a watchful eye. To be a blood hunter is to accept a life of solitude until proven trustworthy and dependable.</p>
            <h4>CREATING A BLOOD HUNTER</h4>
            <p>As you create your blood hunter, keep in mind how your character relates to society and why they have taken to a life of monster hunting. Do they inth to protect society and as such have paid the ulitmate price? Do they have a family they inth to protect at all costs? Did they make a mistake that cost them greatly, and they inth to make amends for their folly? Or are they bent on vengeance for some past wounds or loss that drove them to choose this dark warrior’s path?</p>
            <p class="indent">While a blood hunter begins their journey alone, they also acknowledge the strength in numbers and the benefits of trusted companions. Many blood hunters keep allies to both ensure that they succeed at their hunts, and to keep a watchful eye to prevent them from losing touch with their humanity. A blood hunter without conviction in lost, and often an honest friend is enough to keep them from straying.</p>
            <h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
            <p>You can make a blood hunter quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Strength or Dexterity your highest ability score, depending on whether you want to focus on melee weapons, or ranged and finesse weapons. Make intelligence your next highest if you plan to focus on the potency of blood curses and mystical powers. Choose a higher Constitution next if you inth to use Crimson Rite on multiple weapons or want to have extra hit points to burn on amplifying blood curses. Then, select the Haunted One or Acolyte background.</p>
            <h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
            <p>As a blood hunter, you gain the following class features.</p>
            <h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
            <p>
                <span class="emphasis">Hit Dice:</span>1d10 per blood hunter level
                <br />
                <span class="emphasis">Hit Points at 1st Level:</span>10 + your Constitution modifier
                <br />
                <span class="emphasis">Hit Points at Higher Levels:</span>1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per blood hunter level after 1st
            </p>
            <h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
            <p>
                <span class="emphasis">Armor:</span>Light armor, medium armor, shields 
                <br />
                <span class="emphasis">Weapons:</span>Simple weapons, martial weapons 
                <br />
                <span class="emphasis">Tools:</span>Alchemist’s supplies 
            </p>
            <p>
                <span class="emphasis">Saving Throws:</span>Strength, intelligence 
                <br />
                <span class="emphasis">Skills:</span>Choose two skills from Athletics, Acrobatics, Arcana, History, Insight, Investigation, and Survival 
            </p>
            <h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
            <p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
            <ul>
                <li>
                    <i>(a)</i> a martial weapon or 
                    <i>(b)</i> two simple weapons 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>(a)</i> a light crossbow and 20 bolts or 
                    <i>(b)</i> hand crossbow and 20 bolts 
                </li>
                <li>
                    <i>(a)</i> studded leather armor or 
                    <i>(b)</i> scale mail armor 
                </li>
                <li> an explorer’s pack </li>
            </ul>
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_HUNTERS_BANE" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_CRIMSON_RITE" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_MALEDICT" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_BLOODHUNTER" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_GRIM_PSYCHOMETRY" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_DARK_VELOCITY" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_HARDENED_SOUL" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_SANGUINE_MASTERY" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="short">A hunter that sacrifices his own vitality and humanity to protect the realms.</set>
            <set name="hd">d10</set>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://www.dmsguild.com/product/170777/Blood-Hunter-Class</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false"/>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_CRIT_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_CRIT_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_CRIT_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_CRIT_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_CRIT_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" requirements="!ID_CRIT_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" requirements="!ID_CRIT_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_intelligence" requirements="!ID_CRIT_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER"/>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Blood Hunter)" supports="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ATHLETICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ACROBATICS|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_HISTORY|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INSIGHT|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION|ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_SURVIVAL" number="2" requirements="!ID_CRIT_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER"/>
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_HUNTERS_BANE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_CRIMSON_RITE" level="1" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_MALEDICT" level="2" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER" level="3" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_BLOODHUNTER" level="4" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_GRIM_PSYCHOMETRY" level="9" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_DARK_VELOCITY" level="10" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_HARDENED_SOUL" level="14" />
            <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_SANGUINE_MASTERY" level="20" />
        </rules>
        <multiclass id="ID_CRIT_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER">
            <prerequisite>Strength 13 or Dexterity 13, and intelligence 13</prerequisite>
            <requirements>([str:13]||[dex:13]),[int:13],!ID_DMSG_MMBH_CLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER,!ID_DMSG_MMBH_MULTICLASS_BLOOD_HUNTER</requirements>
            <setters>
                <set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons, alchemical supplies</set>
            </setters>
            <rules>
                <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
                <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_ALCHEMISTS_SUPPLIES" />
            </rules>
        </multiclass>
    </element>
    <element name="Hunter’s Bane" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_HUNTERS_BANE">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 1st level, you have survived the inbibing of the Hunter’s Bane, a poisonous alchemical concoction that alters your life’s blood, forever binding you to the darkness and honing your senses against it.</p>
            <p class="indent">You have advantage on intelligence (Survival) checks to track Fey, Fiends, and Undead, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them. If you are actively tracking one of these creatures types, you cannot be surprised by any creatures of that type. You can only be tracking one type of creature at a time.</p>
            <p class="indent">Upon reaching 11th level, you can flare the internal toxic scars from the ritual, using the pain to give clarity, or promote anger. You can choose to suffer damage equal to a roll of your crimson rite damage die to gain advantage on a intelligence (Insight) check or Charisma (Intimidation) check.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on Survival checks to track Fey, Fiends, and Undead as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them. If you are actively tracking one of these creatures types, you cannot be surprised by any creatures of that type. You can only be tracking one type of creature at a time.</description>
            <description level="11">You have advantage on Survival checks to track Fey, Fiends, and Undead as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them. If you are actively tracking one of these creatures types, you cannot be surprised by any creatures of that type. You can only be tracking one type of creature at a time. You can choose to suffer damage equal to a roll of your crimson rite damage die to gain advantage on a Insight check or Intimidation check.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Crimson Rite" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_CRIMSON_RITE">
        <description>
            <p>At 1st level, you learn to invoke a rite of blood magic within your weapon at the cost of your own vitality. Choose to learn one rite from the Primal Rites list below. You cannot change this choice.</p>
            <p class="indent">As a bonus action, you imbue a single weapon with the elemental energy of a known rite until your next short or long rest. While active, attacks from this weapon deal an additional 1d4 rite damage of the chosen elemental type. Rite damage is considered magical. The rite damage die changes as you gain blood hunter levels, as shown in the crimson rite damage die column of the blood hunter table. Should your weapon leave your grip, the rite fades immediately. An active rite on a weapon thrown fades directly after the attack is complete.</p>
            <p class="indent">When a crimson rite is activated, you suffer damage equal to your character level, and you reduce your maximum hit points by an amount equal to your character level. These lost maximum hit points return once the rite fades and cannot be restored otherinte. When a rite fades, no hit points are regained as part of the restoring of maximum hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent">Crimson rite can be used on multiple weapons, costing additional hit points loss. Most weapons can only be subject to a single rite at any given time. Each end of a polearm or quarterstaff is treated as a seperate weapon for the purposes of this feature. A rite can be allowed to fade at any time on your turn (no action required).</p>
            <p class="indent">You gain access to an additional Primal Rite at 6th level and 11th level. You may learn an Esoteric Rite at 14th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a bonus action, you imbue a single weapon with the elemental energy of a known rite until your next short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Primal Rite" supports="Blood Hunter, Primal Rite" level="1" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Primal Rite" supports="Blood Hunter, Primal Rite" level="6" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Primal Rite" supports="Blood Hunter, Primal Rite" level="11" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Esoteric Rite" supports="Blood Hunter, Esoteric Rite" level="14" />
            <stat name="crimson rite:damage die" value="4" bonus="crimson rite" level="1" />
            <stat name="crimson rite:damage die" value="6" bonus="crimson rite" level="6" />
            <stat name="crimson rite:damage die" value="8" bonus="crimson rite" level="11" />
            <stat name="crimson rite:damage die" value="10" bonus="crimson rite" level="16" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <!-- Primal Rites -->
    <element name="Rite of the Flame" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_PRIMAL_RITE_FLAME">
        <supports>Blood Hunter, Primal Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your rite damage is fire type.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your rite damage is fire type.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Rite of the Frozen" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_PRIMAL_RITE_FROZEN">
        <supports>Blood Hunter, Primal Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your rite damage is cold type.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your rite damage is cold type.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Rite of the Storm" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_PRIMAL_RITE_STORM">
        <supports>Blood Hunter, Primal Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your rite damage is lightning type.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your rite damage is lightning type.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <!-- Esoteric Rites -->
    <element name="Rite of the Roar" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_ESOTERIC_RITE_ROAR">
        <supports>Blood Hunter, Esoteric Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your rite damage is thunder type.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your rite damage is thunder type.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Rite of the Oracle" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_ESOTERIC_RITE_ORACLE">
        <supports>Blood Hunter, Esoteric Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your rite damage is psychic type.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your rite damage is psychic type.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Rite of the Dead" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_ESOTERIC_RITE_DEAD">
        <supports>Blood Hunter, Esoteric Rite</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your rite damage is necrotic type.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your rite damage is necrotic type.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <!-- /Esoteric Rites -->
    <element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_FIGHTING_STYLE">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level, you adopt a style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">ARCHERY</h5>
            <p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">DUELING</h5>
            <p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">GREAT WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
            <p>When you roll a 1 or 2 on a damage die for an attack you make with a melee weapon that you are wielding with two hands, you can reroll the die and must use the new roll, even if the new roll is a 1 or a 2. The weapon must have the two-handed or versatile property for you to gain this benefit.</p>
            <h5 class="caption">TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
            <p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet />
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_ARCHERY|ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_DUELING|ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_GREAT_WEAPON_FIGHTING|ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_FEATURE_FIGHTINGSTYLE_TWOWEAPON_FIGHTING" level="1"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood Maledict" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_MALEDICT">
        <description>
            <p>At 2nd level, you gain the knowledge to further channel, and sacrifice, a part of your vital essence to curse and manipulate your enemies. You gain one blood curse of your choice, detailed in the “blood curses” section below. You learned one additional blood curse of your choice at 5th, 9th, 13th, 16th, and 20th level.</p>
            <p class="indent">When you use your Blood Maledict, you choose which curse to invoke. While invoking a blood curse, but before it affects the target, you may choose to <i>amplify</i> the curse by suffering damage equal to a roll of your crimson rite damage die. An amplified curse gains an additional effect, noted in the curse’s description. Creatures that do not have blood in their bodies are immune to the blood curses (DM’s discretion).</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature once. You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest. Beginning at 6th level, you can use your Blood Maledict feature twice between rests, at 11th level you can use it three times between rests, and at 17th level you can use it four times between rests.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain the knowledge to further channel, and sacrifice, a part of your vital essence to curse and manipulate your enemies. You can use {{blood maledict:curse count}} blood curses / short rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Blood Curse" supports="Blood Curse" level="2" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Blood Curse (5)" supports="Blood Curse" level="5" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Blood Curse (9)" supports="Blood Curse" level="9" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Blood Curse (13)" supports="Blood Curse" level="13" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Blood Curse (16)" supports="Blood Curse" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Blood Curse (20)" supports="Blood Curse" level="20" />
            <stat name="blood maledict:curse count" value="1" level="2" />
            <stat name="blood maledict:curse count" value="1" level="6" />
            <stat name="blood maledict:curse count" value="1" level="11" />
            <stat name="blood maledict:curse count" value="1" level="17" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood Hunter Order" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you commit to an order of blood hunter martial focus. Choose Order of the Mutant, Order of the Ghostslayer, or Order of the Profane Soul, all detailed at the end of the class description. The order you choose grants you features at 3rd level, and again at 7th, 11th, 15th, and 18th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype" name="Blood Hunter Order" supports="Blood Hunter Order" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Ability Score Improvement" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_ABILITYSCOREIMPROVEMENT_BLOODHUNTER">
		<compendium display="false" />
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet display="false" />
        <rules>
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Blood Hunter 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Blood Hunter,4" level="4" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Blood Hunter 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Blood Hunter,8" level="8" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Blood Hunter 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Blood Hunter,12" level="12" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Blood Hunter 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Blood Hunter,16" level="16" />
            <select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Blood Hunter 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Blood Hunter,19" level="19" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
		</rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Grim Psychometry" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_GRIM_PSYCHOMETRY">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 9th level, you can take 10 minutes to meditate on an object to discern vague details regarding any lingering evil or wicked past surrounding it. Make a intelligence ability check. Based on the result, the DM may reveal obscure information about dark events that may have previously surrounded the object, or hints towards a sinister purpose. This feature has no effect on objects untouched by evil. An object can only be targeted by this feature once, and future attempts reveal no further details.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can take 10 minutes to meditate on an object to discern vague details regarding any lingering evil or wicked past surrounding it.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Dark Velocity" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_DARK_VELOCITY">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching 10th level, you beckon the surrounding shadows to grant you unnatural swiftness on the battlefield. You gain darkvision out to 30 feet, or if you have darkvision, extend it out an additional 30 feet. While in dim light or darkness, your speed increases by 10 feet, and attacks of opportunity made against you have disadvantage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain darkvision out to 30 feet, or if you have darkvision, extend it out an additional 30 feet. While in dim light or darkness, your speed increases by 10 feet, and attacks of opportunity made against you have disadvantage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_DARKVISION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Hardened Soul" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_HARDENED_SOUL">
        <description>
            <p>When you reach 14th level, you can no longer become Frightened, and you have advantage on saving throws against magical Charm effects.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can no longer become Frightened, and you have advantage on saving throws against magical Charm effects.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Sanguine Mastery" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_SANGUINE_MASTERY">
        <description>
            <p>Upon becoming 20th level, your ability to harness your pain, and the pain of your foes, is perfected. When you are below one fourth of your current maximum hit points, all of your crimson rite damage dice are maximized.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, when you critically hit when a weapon attack that bears your crimson rite, you regain a use of your blood maledict feature.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you are below one fourth of your current maximum hit points, all of your crimson rite damage dice are maximized. In addition, when you critically hit when a weapon attack that bears your crimson rite, you regain a use of your blood maledict feature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <!-- Blood Curses -->
    <element name="Blood Curse of Binding" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_BINDING">
        <supports>Blood Curse</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can attempt to bind an enemy no more than one size larger than you within 30 feet. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier) or have their speed be reduced to 0 until the end of your next turn.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Amplify.</i></b> This curse becomes ongoing, and can affect a creature regardless of their size category. At the end of each of its turns, the cursed can make another Strength saving throw. On a success, this curse ends. You can end the curse whenever you like (no action required).
                                    
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a bonus action, you can attempt to bind an enemy no more than one size larger than you within 30 feet. The target must succeed on a Strength saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier) or have their speed be reduced to 0 until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood Curse of the Eyeless" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_THE_EYELESS">
        <supports>Blood Curse</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When an enemy who is not immune to blindness within 60 feet makes a weapon attack, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Amplify.</i></b> Following the triggering attack, the affected enemy has disadvantage on the next attack roll they make.
                                    
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When an enemy who is not immune to blindness within 60 feet makes a weapon attack, you can use your reaction to impose disadvantage on the attack roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood Curse of the Fallen Puppet" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_THE_FALLEN_PUPPET">
        <supports>Blood Curse</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The moment a creature falls unconscious or dies within 30 feet of you, you can use your reaction to give that creature a final act of aggression. That creature immediately makes a single weapon attack against a target of your choice within its attack range. After the attack, the creature returns to being unconscious or dead.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Amplify.</i></b> You grant a bonus to the attack roll and damage roll of the cursed creature’s attack equal to your intelligence modifier (minimum of 1).
                                    
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use your reaction to give that creature a final act of aggression. That creature immediately makes a single weapon attack against a target of your choice within its attack range.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood Curse of the Fending Rite" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_THE_FENDING_RITE">
        <supports>Blood Curse</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When an enemy casts a spell that requires a Dexterity saving throw, you can use your reaction to deflect the spell with your crimson rite. You gain a bonus to the initial saving throw against that spell equall to your intelligence modifier (minimum of 1). This curse is invoked before the saving throw is rolled.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Amplify.</i></b> You grant all allies within 5 feet of you this bonus to their saving throw against the triggering spell as well.
                                    
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When an enemy casts a spell that requires a Dexterity saving throw, you can use your reaction to deflect the spell with your crimson rite. You gain a +{{intelligence:modifier}} bonus to the initial saving throw against that spell.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood Curse of the Marked" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_THE_MARKED">
        <supports>Blood Curse</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can mark an enemy within 60 feet. Until the end of your turn, all crimson rite damage you deal to the target is doubled.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Amplify.</i></b> You cause the marked target to also lose resistance to your rite damage type until the beginning of your next turn.
                                    
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a bonus action, you can mark an enemy within 60 feet. Until the end of your turn, all crimson rite damage you deal to the target is doubled.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood Curse of Mutual Suffering" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_MUTUAL_SUFFERING">
        <supports>Blood Curse</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can link to a creature within 30 feet for up to a minute, forcing them to share in the pain they inflict upon you. The next time the cursed creature damages you with a weapon attack, this curse deals necrotic damage to the cursed creature equal to half of the damage you suffered. This curse then ends.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Amplify.</i></b> This curse instead deals damage equal to the damage you suffered, and it ignores Necrotic resistance.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a bonus action, you can link to a creature within 30 feet for up to a minute, forcing them to share in the pain they inflict upon you. The next time the cursed creature damages you with a weapon attack, this curse deals necrotic damage to the cursed creature equal to half of the damage you suffered. This curse then ends.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood Curse of Purgation" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_PURGATION">
        <supports>Blood Curse</supports>
        <description>
            <p>As a bonus action, you can manipulate the vitality of a creature within 60 feet to expunge a corruption in their blood. The target creature can immediately make a saving throw against a poisoned condition afflicting it.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Amplify.</i></b> Your target can instead immediately make a saving throw against one othercondition afflicting it. This condition can be linded, deafened, or paralyzed.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As a bonus action, you can manipulate the vitality of a creature within 60 feet to expunge a corruption in their blood. The target creature can immediately make a saving throw against a poisoned condition afflicting it.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood Curse of Spell Sunder" type="Class Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_CLASS_FEATURE_BLOOD_HUNTER_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_SPELL_SUNDER">
        <supports>Blood Curse</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When an enemy casts a spell within 60 feet that requires a spell attack roll and targets you, you can use your reaction to rend the spell from the air, imposing disadvantage on the spell attack roll.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Amplify.</i></b> You make a intelligence ability check. The DC equals 10 + the spell’s level. On a success, the creature’s spel misses you automatically.
                                    
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When an enemy casts a spell within 60 feet that requires a spell attack roll and targets you, you can use your reaction to rend the spell from the air, imposing disadvantage on the spell attack roll.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <!-- /Blood Curses -->

    <!-- Ghostslayer -->
    <element name="Order of the Ghostslayer" type="Archetype" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_GHOSTSLAYER">
        <supports>Blood Hunter Order</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The Order of the Ghostslayer is the oldest and most driven of the orders, having rediscovered the secrets of blood magic and refined them for combat against the scourge of undeath. Ghostslayers seek out and study the moment of death, obsessing over the mysteries of the transition. Some will sit with the terminally diseased to closely witness their passing, while others go so far as to deliberately have a near-death experience, allowing them to tune their body and senses to the ethereal realms beyond.</p>
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_RITE_OF_THE_DAWN" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_HALLOWED_VEINS" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_SUPERNAL_SURGE" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_GRAVESIGHT" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_VENGEFUL_SPIRIT" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://www.dmsguild.com/product/170777/Blood-Hunter-Class</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>The Order of the Ghostslayer is the oldest and most driven of the orders, having rediscovered the secrets of blood magic and refined them for combat against the scourge of undeath.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_RITE_OF_THE_DAWN" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_HALLOWED_VEINS" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_SUPERNAL_SURGE" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_GRAVESIGHT" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_VENGEFUL_SPIRIT" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rite of the Dawn" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_RITE_OF_THE_DAWN">
        <description>
            <p>When you join this order at 3rd level, you learn the esoteric rite Rite of the Dawn (detailed below).</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Rite of the Dawn.</i></b> Your rite damage is radiant type.
                                    
            </p>
            <p class="indent">If you hit an Undead creature with your Rite of the Dawn, it suffers additional radiant damage equal to your intelligence modifier.</p>
            <p class="indent">Upon reaching 11th level, any creature you hit with your Rite of the Dawn suffers this additional radiant damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>If you hit an Undead creature with your Rite of the Dawn, it suffers {{intelligence:modifier}} additional radiant damage.</description>
            <description level="11">If you hit a creature with your Rite of the Dawn, it suffers {{intelligence:modifier}} additional radiant damage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_ESOTERIC_RITE_DAWN" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Rite of the Dawn" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_ESOTERIC_RITE_DAWN">
        <!-- <supports>Blood Hunter, Esoteric Rite</supports> -->
        <description>
            <p>Your rite damage is radiant type.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your rite damage is radiant type.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Hallowed Veins" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_HALLOWED_VEINS">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 7th level, your blood curses become honed to the fabric of a creature’s essence. Your blood curses can now affect any creature, regardless of their form or lack of blood.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, when you target an undead creature with a blood curse, it must succeed on a intelligence saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier) or it cannot target you with an attack until the end of your next turn.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your blood curses can now affect any creature, regardless of their form or lack of blood. In addition, when you target an undead creature with a blood curse, it must succeed on a intelligence saving throw (DC equal to 8 + your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier) or it cannot target you with an attack until the end of your next turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Supernal Surge" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_SUPERNAL_SURGE">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching 11th level, you’ve learned to briefly step into the spirit world, enabling a swift and deadly strike. When you use that Attack action, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action, and you temporarily become spectral. Until the end of your next turn, you can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. You take 1d10 force damage if you end your turn inside an object. If you are inside an object when and you are no longer spectral, you are immediately shunted to the nearest unoccupied space that you can occupy and take force damage equal to twice the number of feet you moved. You may expend a use of this feature as a bonus action instead of making an attack.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature a number of times equal to your intelligence modifier (a minimum of once). You regain all expended uses when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you use that Attack action, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action, and you temporarily become spectral. Until the end of your next turn, you can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. You take 1d10 force damage if you end your turn inside an object. If you are inside an object when and you are no longer spectral, you are immediately shunted to the nearest unoccupied space that you can occupy and take force damage equal to twice the number of feet you moved. You may expend a use of this feature as a bonus action instead of making an attack. ({{intelligence:modifier}}/SR)</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Gravesight" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_GRAVESIGHT">
        <description>
            <p>At 15th level, you can see in magical darkness up to 30 feet, as well as see invisible creatures and object up to 30 feet.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can see in magical darkness up to 30 feet, as well as see invisible creatures and object up to 30 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Vengeful Spirit" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_GHOSTSLAYER_VENGEFUL_SPIRIT">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching 18th level, you learn to project your spirit to fight on while on the edge of death. Whenever your hit points drop to 0, you can choose to let your soul emerge from your body to fight on. Your body remains unconscious and subject to death saving throws per normal. At the beginning of your next turn, you manifest a spirit form in your space that picks up your weapons and continues fighting on, acting on your turn and every one of your subsequent turns under your control. Your spirit form has your physical attributes and armor class, as well as your weapons and ammunition, and can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. This form is immune to cold, necrotic, and non-magical weapon damage. Your spirit form has access to all of your abilities and suffers no damage from your Crimson Rite feature.</p>
            <p class="indent">If your spirit form takes any damage, your body dies, or you regain any hit points, your spirit form vanishes. If your spirit form vanishes, it drops your weapons in its space.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever your hit points drop to 0, you can choose to let your soul emerge from your body to fight on. Your body remains unconscious and subject to death saving throws per normal. At the beginning of your next turn, you manifest a spirit form in your space that picks up your weapons and continues fighting on, acting on your turn and every one of your subsequent turns under your control. Your spirit form has your physical attributes and armor class, as well as your weapons and ammunition, and can move through other creatures and objects as if they were difficult terrain. This form is immune to cold, necrotic, and non-magical weapon damage. Your spirit form has access to all of your abilities and suffers no damage from your Crimson Rite feature.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <!-- /Ghostslayer -->

    <!-- Profane Soul -->
	<element name="Order of the Profane Soul" type="Archetype" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_PROFANE_SOUL">
		<supports>Blood Hunter Order</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The magics adopted by the wayward blood hunter prove formidable against many an evil across the realm. However, the darkest of abominations draw from an ancient well of cruel, unfathomable power. These terrors can control shadows to do their bidding, hide in plain sight among the noblest of nobles, and bend the minds of the most stalwart warrior with but a glance. These fiends are far trickier to hunt, and many lost their lives in pursuit of such wickedness.</p>
			<p class="indent">A small sect of blood hunters had finally had enough and delved into this same well of corrupting arcane knowledge, making pacts with lesser evils to better combat the greater. While they may have lost a part of themselves, the power gained far outweighed the price, for even devils now quake when they know they’ve drawn the attention of the Order of the Profane Soul.</p>
			<div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_PACT_MAGIC" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_MYSTIC_FRENZY" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_DIABOLIC_CHANNEL" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA" />
			<div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_SOUL_SYPHON" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>The magics adopted by the wayward blood hunter prove formidable against many an evil across the realm.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_PACT_MAGIC" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_MYSTIC_FRENZY" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_DIABOLIC_CHANNEL" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA" level="15" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_SOUL_SYPHON" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Otherworldly Patron" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you strike a bargan with an other-worldy being of your choice: the Archfey, the Fiend, or the Great Old One, each detailed on page 109 of the PHB, the Undying on page 139 of the Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide, and the Hexblade or Celestial on page 54 of Xanathar’s Guide to Everything. Your choice augments some of your order features.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="true" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Otherworldly Patron" supports="Profane Soul Otherworldly Patron" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Pact Magic" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_PACT_MAGIC">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 3rd level, you can augment your combat techniques with the ability to cast spells. See chapter 10 (phb) for the general rules of spellcasting and chapter 11 (phb) for the Warlock spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Cantrips.</em></strong> You learn two cantrips of your choice from the warlock spell list. You learn an additional warlock cantrip of your choice at 10th level.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Spell Slots.</em></strong> The Profane Soul Spellcasting table shows how many spell slots you have. The table also shows what the level of those slots is; all of your spell slots are the same level. To cast one of your warlock spells of 1st level or higher, you must expend a spell slot. You regain all expended spell slots when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">For example, when you are 8th level, you have two 2nd­-level spell slots. To cast the 1st-level spell witch bolt, you must spend one of those slots, and you cast it as a 2nd-level spell.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Spells Known of 1st Level and Higher.</em></strong> At 3rd level, you know two 1st-level spells of your choice from the warlock spell list.</p>
			<p class="indent">The Spells Known column of the Profane Soul table shows when you learn more warlock spells of your choice of 1st-level and higher. A spell you choose must be of a level no higher than what’s shown in the table’s Slot Level column for your level. When you reach 11th-level, for example, you learn a new warlock spell, which can be 1st, 2nd, or 3rd level.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a level in this class and order, you can choose one of the warlock spells you know and replace is with another spell from the warlock spell list, which also must be of a level for which you have spell slots.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>Spellcasting Ability.</em></strong> intelligence is your spellcasting ability for your warlock spells, so you use your intelligence whenever a spell refers to your spellcasting ability. In addition, you use your intelligence modifier when setting the saving throw DC for a warlock spell you cast and when making an attack roll with one.</p>
			<center>
				<p><strong>Spell save DC = 8</strong> + your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier</p>
				<p><strong>Spell attack modifier =</strong> your proficiency bonus + your intelligence modifier</p>
			</center>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>You can augment your combat techniques with the ability to cast spells.</description>
		</sheet>
		<spellcasting name="Profane Soul" ability="intelligence" allowReplace="true">
			<list>Warlock</list>
		</spellcasting>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS_SPELLCASTING_SLOTS_SOLO" requirements="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS"/>

			<stat name="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="3"/>
			<stat name="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="5"/>
			<stat name="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:count" value="1" level="14"/>

			<stat name="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:1" value="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:count" level="3" />
			<stat name="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:1" value="-profane soul:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
			<stat name="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:2" value="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:count" level="7" />
			<stat name="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:2" value="-profane soul:spellcasting:slots:count" level="11" />
			<stat name="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:3" value="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:count" level="11" />
			<stat name="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:3" value="-profane soul:spellcasting:slots:count" level="17" />
			<stat name="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:4" value="profane soul:spellcasting:slots:count" level="17" />

			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Profane Soul" />
			<select type="Spell" name="Cantrip (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),0" level="10" spellcasting="Profane Soul" />

			<select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="3" number="2" spellcasting="Profane Soul"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="5" spellcasting="Profane Soul"/>		
			<select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="7" spellcasting="Profane Soul"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="9" spellcasting="Profane Soul"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="11" spellcasting="Profane Soul"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="13" spellcasting="Profane Soul"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="15" spellcasting="Profane Soul"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="17" spellcasting="Profane Soul"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="19" spellcasting="Profane Soul"/>
			<select type="Spell" name="Pact Magic (Profane Soul)" supports="$(spellcasting:list),$(spellcasting:slots)" level="20" spellcasting="Profane Soul"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Rite Focus" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS">
		<description>
			<p>Begining at 3rd level, your weapon becomes a core to your pact with your chosen dark patron. While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus (found in chapter 5, player’s hand book) for your spells. Your chosen pact also enhances your rite (outlined below).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Archfey.</em></strong> If you deal rite damage to a creature, that creature loses any half or three-quarters cover bonuses, as well as invisibility, until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Fiend.</em></strong> While using the Rite of the Flame, if you roll a 1 on your rite damage die, you may reroll the die. You may reroll only once per attack.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Great Old One.</em></strong> Whenever you deal a critical hit to a creature, that creature must make a intelligence saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the creature is frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Undying.</em></strong> Whenever you reduce a hostile creature to 0 hit points with a weapon attack, and kill it, you regain hit points equal to your crimson rite damage die.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Celestial.</em></strong> You can expend a use of your blood maledict feature as a bonus action to heal one creature within 60 feet of you. They regain hit points equal to your crimson rite damage die rolled twice + your intelligence modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Hexblade.</em></strong> Whenever you target a creature with a blood curse, your next attack against the cursed creature is a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_FIEND" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_FIEND" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_ARCHFEY" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_ARCHFEY" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_GREAT_OLD_ONE" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_GREAT_OLD_ONE" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_UNDYING" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_UNDYING" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_CELESTIAL" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_CELESTIAL" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_HEXBLADE" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_HEXBLADE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Mystic Frenzy" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_MYSTIC_FRENZY">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 7th level, when you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you use your action to cast a cantrip, you can make one weapon attack as a bonus action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Revealed Arcana" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA">
		<description>
			<p>At 7th level, your dark patron grants you the rare use of a dangerous arcane spell based on your pact.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Archfey.</em></strong> You can cast <em>blur</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Fiend.</em></strong> You can cast <em>scorching ray</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Great Old One.</em></strong> You can cast <em>detect thoughts</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Undying.</em></strong> You can cast <em>blindness/deafness</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Celestial.</em></strong> You can cast <em>lesser restoration</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Hexblade.</em></strong> You can cast <em>branding smite</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Your dark patron grants you the rare use of a dangerous arcane spell based on your pact.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_FIEND" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_FIEND" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_ARCHFEY" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_ARCHFEY" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_GREAT_OLD_ONE" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_GREAT_OLD_ONE" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_UNDYING" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_UNDYING" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_CELESTIAL" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_CELESTIAL" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_HEXBLADE" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_HEXBLADE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Diabolic Channel" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_DIABOLIC_CHANNEL">
		<description>
			<p>At 11th level, you can temporarily infuse your rite with the seed of a powerful spell. As an action, you can imbue your rite-enhanced weapon with one warlock spell you can cast or is already active, then make a single attack with that weapon. The spell must be using a warlock or profane soul spell slot. If that attack hits, all spell attack rolls for the imbued spell hit the target automatically and are considered part of the single weapon attack. The target takes weapon damage, and is subject to the effects of the spell, expending a spell slot accordingly. If the attack has advantage, the target’s initial saving throw against the spell has disadvantage. If the attack misses, the spell has no effect. Area spells originate from the target’s space.</p>
			<p class="indent">The spell must be of 1st level or higher, have a casting time of 1 action, or require an action to activate an already active concentration spell.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Action">
			<description>You can imbue your rite-enhanced weapon with one warlock spell you can cast or is already active, then make a single attack with that weapon. The spell must be using a warlock or profane soul spell slot. If that attack hits, all spell attack rolls for the imbued spell hit the target automatically and are considered part of the single weapon attack. The target takes weapon damage, and is subject to the effects of the spell, expending a spell slot accordingly. If the attack has advantage, the target’s initial saving throw against the spell has disadvantage. If the attack misses, the spell has no effect. Area spells originate from the target’s space.
			The spell must be of 1st level or higher, have a casting time of 1 action, or require an action to activate an already active concentration spell.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>

		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Unsealed Arcana" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA">
		<description>
			<p>At 15th level, your dark patron grants you the rare use of an additional arcane spell based on your pact.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Archfey.</em></strong> You can cast <em>slow</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Fiend.</em></strong> You can cast <em>fireball</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. </p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Great Old One.</em></strong>  You can cast <em>haste</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Undying.</em></strong> You can cast <em>bestow curse</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Celestial.</em></strong> You can cast <em>revivify</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent"><strong><em>The Hexblade.</em></strong> You can cast <em>blink</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description>Your dark patron grants you the rare use of an additional arcane spell based on your pact.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_FIEND" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_FIEND" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_ARCHFEY" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_ARCHFEY" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_GREAT_OLD_ONE" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_GREAT_OLD_ONE" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_UNDYING" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_UNDYING" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_CELESTIAL" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_CELESTIAL" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_HEXBLADE" requirements="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_HEXBLADE" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Soul Syphon" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_SOUL_SYPHON">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 18th level, your learn to sacrifice the souls of powerful foes to your dark patron in exchange for immediate power. When you recduce a creature to 0 hit points with an attack, kill the creature, and they have a challenge rating of 15 or above, you recover an expended spell slot.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you recduce a creature to 0 hit points with an attack, kill the creature, and they have a challenge rating of 15 or above, you recover an expended spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- patrons -->
	<element name="The Fiend" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_FIEND">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Profane Soul Otherworldly Patron</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have made a pact with a fiend from the lower planes of existence, a being whose aims are evil, even if you strive against those aims. Such beings desire the corruption or destruction of all things, ultimately including you. Fiends powerful enough to forge a pact include demon lords such as Demogorgon, Orcus, Fraz’Urb-luu, and Baphomet; archdevils such as Asmodeus, Dispater, Mephistopheles, and Belial; pit fiends and balors that are especially mighty; and ultroloths and other lords of the yugoloths.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have made a pact with a fiend from the lower planes of existence.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="The Archfey" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_ARCHFEY">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Profane Soul Otherworldly Patron</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your patron is a lord or lady of the fey, a creature of legend who holds secrets that were forgotten before the mortal races were born. This being’s motivations are often inscrutable, and sometimes whimsical, and might involve a striving for greater magical power or the settling of age-old grudges. Beings of this sort include the Prince of Frost; the Queen of Air and Darkness, ruler of the Gloaming Court; Titania of the Summer Court; her consort Oberon, the Green Lord; Hyrsam, the Prince of Fools; and ancient hags.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your patron is a lord or lady of the fey, a creature of legend who holds secrets that were forgotten before the mortal races were born.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="The Great Old One" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_GREAT_OLD_ONE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Profane Soul Otherworldly Patron</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your patron is a mysterious entity whose nature is utterly foreign to the fabric of reality. It might come from the Far Realm, the space beyond reality, or it could be one of the elder gods known only in legends. Its motives are incomprehensible to mortals, and its knowledge so immense and ancient that even the greatest libraries pale in comparison to the vast secrets it holds. The Great Old One might be unaware of your existence or entirely indifferent to you, but the secrets you have learned allow you to draw your magic from it.</p>
			<p class="indent">Entities of this type include Ghaunadar, called That Which Lurks; Tharizdun, the Chained God; Dendar, the Night Serpent; Zargon, the Returner; Great Cthulhu; and other unfathomable beings.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your patron is a mysterious entity whose nature is utterly foreign to the fabric of reality.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="The Undying" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_UNDYING">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Profane Soul Otherworldly Patron</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Death holds no sway over your patron, who has unlocked the secrets of everlasting life, although such a prize- like all power- comes at a price. Once mortal, the Undying has seen mortal lifetimes pass like the seasons, like the flicker of endless days and nights. It has the secrets of the ages to share, secrets of life and death. Beings of this sort include Vecna, Lord of the Hand and the Eye; the dread Iuz; the lich-queen Vol; the Undying Court of Aerenal; Vlaakith, lich-queen of the githyanki; and the deathless wizard Fistandantalus.</p>
			<p class="indent">In the Realms, Undying patrons include Larloch the Shadow King, legendary master of Warlock's Crypt, and Gilgeam, the God-King of Unther.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Death holds no sway over your patron, who has unlocked the secrets of everlasting life, although such a prize- like all power- comes at a price.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="The Celestial" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_CELESTIAL">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Profane Soul Otherworldly Patron</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your patron is a powerful being of the Upper Planes. You have bound yourself to an ancient empyrean, solar, ki-rin, or unicorn or to another entity that resides in the planes of everlasting bliss. Your pact with that being allows you to experience the barest touch of the holy light that illuminates the multiverse.</p>
			<p class="indent">Being connected to such power can cause changes in your behavior and beliefs. You might find yourself driven to annihilate the undead, to defeat fiends, and to protect the innocent. At times, your heart might also be filled with a longing for the celestial realm of your patron, a desire to wander that paradise for the rest of your days. But you know that your mission is among mortals for now and that your pact binds you to bring light to the dark places of the world.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your patron is a powerful being of the Upper Planes.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="The Hexblade" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_OTHERWORLDLY_PATRON_HEXBLADE">
		<compendium display="false" />
		<supports>Profane Soul Otherworldly Patron</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have made your pact with a mysterious entity from the Shadowfell—a force that manifests in sentient magic weapons carved from the stuff of shadow. The mighty sword Blackrazor is the most notable of these weapons, which have been spread across the multiverse over the ages. The shadowy force behind these weapons can offer power to warlocks who form pacts with it. Many hexbade warlocks create weapons that emulate those formed in the Shadowfell. Others forgo such arms, content to weave the dark magic of that plane into their spellcasting.</p>
			<p class="indent">Because the Raven Queen is known to have forged the first of these weapons, many sages speculate that she and the force are one and that the weapons, along with hexblade warlocks, are tools she uses to manipulate events on the Material Plane to her inscrutable ends. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have made your pact with a mysterious entity from the Shadowfell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- patron based rite focus -->
	<element name="Rite Focus (The Fiend)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_FIEND">
		<description>
			<p>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.</p>
			<p>If you deal rite damage to a creature, that creature loses any half or three-quarters cover bonuses, as well as invisibility, until the beginning of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Rite Focus">
			<description>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.
			If you deal rite damage to a creature, that creature loses any half or three-quarters cover bonuses, as well as invisibility, until the beginning of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Rite Focus (The Archfey)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_ARCHFEY">
		<description>
			<p>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.</p>
			<p>While using the Rite of the Flame, if you roll a 1 on your rite damage die, you may reroll the die. You may reroll only once per attack.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Rite Focus">
			<description>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.
			While using the Rite of the Flame, if you roll a 1 on your rite damage die, you may reroll the die. You may reroll only once per attack.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Rite Focus (The Great Old One)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_GREAT_OLD_ONE">
		<description>
			<p>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.</p>
			<p>Whenever you deal a critical hit to a creature, that creature must make a intelligence saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the creature is frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Rite Focus">
			<description>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.
			Whenever you deal a critical hit to a creature, that creature must make a intelligence saving throw against your spell save DC. On a failure, the creature is frightened of you until the end of your next turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Rite Focus (The Undying)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_UNDYING">
		<description>
			<p>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.</p>
			<p>Whenever you reduce a hostile creature to 0 hit points with a weapon attack, and kill it, you regain hit points equal to your crimson rite damage die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Rite Focus">
			<description>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.
			Whenever you reduce a hostile creature to 0 hit points with a weapon attack, and kill it, you regain hit points equal to your crimson rite damage die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Rite Focus (The Celestial)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_CELESTIAL">
		<description>
			<p>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.</p>
			<p>You can expend a use of your blood maledict feature as a bonus action to heal one creature within 60 feet of you. They regain hit points equal to your crimson rite damage die rolled twice + your intelligence modifier (minimum of 1).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Rite Focus">
			<description>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.
			You can expend a use of your blood maledict feature as a bonus action to heal one creature within 60 feet of you. They regain hit points equal to {{celestial-rite-focus:hit points}} + your crimson rite damage die rolled twice.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="celestial-rite-focus:hit points" value="1" />
			<stat name="celestial-rite-focus:hit points" value="intelligence:modifier" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Rite Focus (The Hexblade)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_RITE_FOCUS_HEXBLADE">
		<description>
			<p>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.</p>
			<p>Whenever you target a creature with a blood curse, your next attack against the cursed creature is a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Rite Focus">
			<description>While you have an active rite, you can use your weapon as a spellcasting focus for your spells.
			Whenever you target a creature with a blood curse, your next attack against the cursed creature is a critical hit on a roll of 19 or 20 on the d20.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<!-- patron based revealed arcana -->
	<element name="Revealed Arcana (The Fiend)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_FIEND">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>blur</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Revealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>blur</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Revealed Arcana (The Archfey)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_ARCHFEY">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>scorching ray</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Revealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>scorching ray</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Revealed Arcana (The Great Old One)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_GREAT_OLD_ONE">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>detect thoughts</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Revealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>detect thoughts</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Revealed Arcana (The Undying)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_UNDYING">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>blindness/deafness</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Revealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>blindness/deafness</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Revealed Arcana (The Celestial)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_CELESTIAL">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>lesser restoration</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Revealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>lesser restoration</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Revealed Arcana (The Hexblade)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_REVEALED_ARCANA_HEXBLADE">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>branding smite</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Revealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>branding smite</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	
	<!-- patron based unsealed arcana -->
	<element name="Unsealed Arcana (The Fiend)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_FIEND">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>slow</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Unsealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>slow</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Unsealed Arcana (The Archfey)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_ARCHFEY">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>fireball</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Unsealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>fireball</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Unsealed Arcana (The Great Old One)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_GREAT_OLD_ONE">
		<description>
			<p> You can cast <em>haste</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Unsealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description> You can cast <em>haste</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Unsealed Arcana (The Undying)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_UNDYING">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>bestow curse</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Unsealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>bestow curse</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Unsealed Arcana (The Celestial)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_CELESTIAL">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>revivify</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Unsealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>revivify</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Unsealed Arcana (The Hexblade)" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_PROFANE_SOUL_UNSEALED_ARCANA_HEXBLADE">
		<description>
			<p>You can cast <em>blink</em> once using a profane soul spell slot. You can’t do so again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Unsealed Arcana" usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>You can cast <em>blink</em> once using a profane soul spell slot.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

    <!-- /Profane Soul -->

    <!-- Order of the Mutant -->
    <element name="Order of the Mutant" type="Archetype" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT">
        <supports>Blood Hunter Order</supports>
        <description>
            <p>The process of consuming the Hunter’s Bane is a painful, scarring, and often fatal experience. Those that survive find themselves irrevocably changed, enhanced. Some found this experience exalting, embracing the ability to alter one’s own physiology through corrupted alchemy.</p>
            <p class="indent">Over generations of experimentation, a spliter order of blood hunters began to emerge, one that focused on brewing toxic elixirs to modify their capabilities in battle, altering their blood and, over time become something beyond human. They called themselves the Order of the Mutant.</p>
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_FORMULAS" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_MUTAGEN_CRAFT" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_ADVANCED_MUTAGEN_CRAFT" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_STRANGE_METABOLISM" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_ROBUST_PHYSIOLOGY" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_EXALTED_MUTATION" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://www.dmsguild.com/product/170777/Blood-Hunter-Class</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>The process of consuming the Hunter’s Bane is a painful, scarring, and often fatal experience.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_FORMULAS" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_MUTAGEN_CRAFT" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_ADVANCED_MUTAGEN_CRAFT" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_STRANGE_METABOLISM" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_ROBUST_PHYSIOLOGY" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_EXALTED_MUTATION" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Formulas" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_FORMULAS">
        <description>
            <p>You begin to uncover forbidden alchemical formulas that temporarily alter your mental and physical abilities.</p>
            <p class="indent">Beginning at 3rd level, you choose to learn three mutagen formulas. Your formula options are detailed at the end of this description. You gain an additional formula at 7th level, 11th level, 15th level, and 18th level.</p>
            <p class="indent">Additionally, when you gain a new mutagen formula, you can choose one of the formulas you already know and replace it with another mutagen formula.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You begin to uncover forbidden alchemical formulas that temporarily alter your mental and physical abilities.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Mutagen Formula (3)" supports="Mutagen Formula" level="3" number="3" />
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Mutagen Formula (7)" supports="Mutagen Formula" level="7" />
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Mutagen Formula (11)" supports="Mutagen Formula" level="11" />
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Mutagen Formula (15)" supports="Mutagen Formula" level="15" />
            <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Mutagen Formula (18)" supports="Mutagen Formula" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Mutagen Craft" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_MUTAGEN_CRAFT">
        <description>
            <p>At 3rd level, you can take a short rest to concoct a single mutagen. Consuming a single mutagen requires a bonus action, and the effects (including side effects) last until you complete a short or long rest to meditate and flush the toxins from your system.</p>
            <p class="indent">Mutagens are designed for your biology. They have no effect on large or larger creatures, and only impart the side effects on other medium or smaller creatures that drink the entire mutagen. They are also unstable by nature, losing their potency over time and becoming inert if not swallowed before you finish your next short or long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your body will begin to better utilize the toxins you instill it with as you grow in power and experience. These advancing mutations may be signified by a Mutagen score.</p>
            <p>
                <b>Mutation Score</b> = your bood hunter level divided by 4, rounded up.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can take a short rest to concoct a single mutagen. Consuming a single mutagen requires a bonus action, and the effects (including side effects) last until you complete a short or long rest to meditate and flush the toxins from your system.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <!-- blood hunter level /4 rounded up -->
            <stat name="mutation score" value="1" bonus="mutagen craft" />
            <stat name="mutation score" value="1" bonus="mutagen craft" level="4" />
            <stat name="mutation score" value="2" bonus="mutagen craft" level="6" />
            <stat name="mutation score" value="2" bonus="mutagen craft" level="8" />
            <stat name="mutation score" value="3" bonus="mutagen craft" level="10" />
            <stat name="mutation score" value="3" bonus="mutagen craft" level="12" />
            <stat name="mutation score" value="4" bonus="mutagen craft" level="14" />
            <stat name="mutation score" value="4" bonus="mutagen craft" level="16" />
            <stat name="mutation score" value="5" bonus="mutagen craft" level="18" />
            <stat name="mutation score" value="5" bonus="mutagen craft" level="20" />
            <stat name="mutagen craft:amount" value="1" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Advanced Mutagen Craft" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_ADVANCED_MUTAGEN_CRAFT">
        <description>
            <p>Upon reaching 7th level, when you take a short rest to concoct a mutagen, you can now create two. Mutagens must be different forumlas, and can be ingested with overlapping effects that last until you finish your next short or long rest. Each mutagent still takes a seperate bonus action to imbibe.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you reach 15th level, you can now create three mutagens during a short rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you take a short rest to concoct a mutagen, you can now create two. Mutagens must be different forumlas, and can be ingested with overlapping effects that last until you finish your next short or long rest.</description>
            <description level="15">When you take a short rest to concoct a mutagen, you can now create three. Mutagens must be different forumlas, and can be ingested with overlapping effects that last until you finish your next short or long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="mutagen craft:amount" value="1" level="7" />
            <stat name="mutagen craft:amount" value="1" level="15" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Strange Metabolism" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_STRANGE_METABOLISM">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 11th level, you can use a bonus action to instill a burst of adrenaline to temporarily restist the negative effects of a mutagen. You can choose to ignore the side effect of a mutagen affecting you for 1 minute.</p>
            <p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you must finish a short or long rest before you can use it again.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can use a bonus action to instill a burst of adrenaline to temporarily restist the negative effects of a mutagen. You can choose to ignore the side effect of a mutagen affecting you for 1 minute. (SR)</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Robust Physiology" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_ROBUST_PHYSIOLOGY">
        <description>
            <p>At 15th level, your body has begun to adapt to toxins and venoms, ignoring their corroding effects. You gain immunity to poison damage and the poisoned condition.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain immunity to poison damage and the poisoned condition.</description>
        </sheet>
	    <rules>
		    <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_IMMUNITY_POISON" />
	    </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Exalted Mutation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_MUTANT_EXALTED_MUTATION">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level, your body has begun producing one of your toxins naturally. Choose one of your known mutagen formulas. You gain the benefits and side effects of this mutagen permanently, at all times. You cannot change this choice of formula after this feature is aqcuired.</p>
            <p class="indent"></p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your body has begun producing one of your toxins naturally. Choose one of your known mutagen formulas. You gain the benefits and side effects of this mutagen permanently, at all times. You cannot change this choice of formula after this feature is aqcuired.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <!-- todo: implement a 'from existing' selection from existing elements existing="true" -->
            <!-- <select type="Archetype Feature" name="Exalted Mutation" supports="Mutagen Formula" existing="true" /> -->
        </rules>
    </element>
    <!-- /Mutant -->
    <!-- Mutagens -->
    <element name="Aether" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_AETHER">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <prerequisite>11th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[blood hunter:11]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level</p>
            <p>You gain a flying speed of 20 feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> You have disadvantage on all Strength and Dexterity ability checks.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain a flying speed of 20 feet. Side effect: You have disadvantage on all Strength and Dexterity ability checks.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Celerity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_CELERITY">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your Dexterity score increases by an amount equal to your mutation score, as does your Dexterity maximum.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> Your intelligence score decreases by amount equal to your mutation score.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your Dexterity score increases by {{mutation score}}, as does your Dexterity maximum. Side effect: Your intelligence score decreases by {{mutation score}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <!-- <stat name="dexterity" value="mutation score" /> -->
            <!-- <stat name="dexterity:max" value="mutation score" /> -->
            <!-- <stat name="intelligence" value="-mutation score" /> -->
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Conversant" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_CONVERSANT">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain advantage on Intelligence ability checks.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> You have disadvantage on Charisma ability checks.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain advantage on Intelligence ability checks. Side effect: You have disadvantage on Charisma ability checks.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Cruelty" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_CRUELTY">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <prerequisite>11th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[blood hunter:11]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level</p>
            <p>You can make a single weapon attack as a bonus action on each of your turns.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> You have disadvantage on all saving throws.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can make a single weapon attack as a bonus action on each of your turns. Side effect: You have disadvantage on all saving throws.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Impermeable" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_IMPERMEABLE">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain resistance to piercing damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> You gain vulnerability to slashing damage.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain resistance to piercing damage. Side effect: You gain vulnerability to slashing damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Mobility" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_MOBILITY">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain immunity to the grappled and restrained conditions. At 11th level, you also are immune to the paralyzed condition.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> You gain a penalty to initiative equal to 2 times your mutation score.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain immunity to the grappled and restrained conditions. Side effect: You gain a -{{mobility formula:penalty}} penalty to initiative.</description>
            <description level="11">You gain immunity to the grappled, restrained, and paralyzed conditions. Side effect: You gain a -{{mobility formula:penalty}} penalty to initiative.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="mobility formula:penalty" value="mutation score" />
            <stat name="mobility formula:penalty" value="mutation score" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Nighteye" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_NIGHTEYE">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain darkvision for up to 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, this increases its range by 60 additional feet.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> You gain sunlight sensitivity.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain darkvision for up to 60 feet. If you already have darkvision, this increases its range by 60 additional feet. Side effect: You gain sunlight sensitivity.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Potency" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_POTENCY">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your Strength score increases by an amount equal to your mutation score, as does your Strength maximum.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> Your Dexterity score decreases by amount equal to your mutation score.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your Strength score increases by {{mutation score}}, as does your Strength maximum. Side effect: Your Dexterity score decreases by {{mutation score}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <!-- <stat name="strength" value="mutation score" /> -->
            <!-- <stat name="strength:max" value="mutation score" /> -->
            <!-- <stat name="dexterity" value="-mutation score" /> -->
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Precision" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_PRECISION">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <prerequisite>11th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[blood hunter:11]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 11th level</p>
            <p>Your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19-20.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> All healing you receive is halved.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your weapon attacks score a critical hit on a roll of 19-20. Side effect: All healing you receive is halved.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Rapidity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_RAPIDITY">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your speed increases by 15 feet. At 15th level, your speed increases by 20 feet instead.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> You have disadvantage on Dexterity ability checks.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your speed increases by 15 feet. Side effect: You have disadvantage on Dexterity ability checks.</description>
            <description level="15">Your speed increases by 20 feet. Side effect: You have disadvantage on Dexterity ability checks.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Reconstruction" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_RECONSTRUCTION">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <prerequisite>7th level</prerequisite>
        <requirements>[blood hunter:7]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p class="flavor">Prerequisite: 7th level</p>
            <p>While conscious and in combat, you regenerate hit points equal to 2 times your mutation score at the start of your turn as long as you are above 0 hit points.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> Your speed decreases by 10 feet.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>While conscious and in combat, you regenerate {{reconstruction formula:regeneration}} hit points at the start of your turn as long as you are above 0 hit points. Side effect: Your speed decreases by 10 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="reconstruction formula:regeneration" value="mutation score" />
            <stat name="reconstruction formula:regeneration" value="mutation score" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Sagacity" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_SAGACITY">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your intelligence score increases by an amount equal to your mutation score, as does your intelligence maximum.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> Your armor class score decreases by amount equal to your mutation score.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your intelligence score increases by {{mutation score}}, as does your intelligence maximum. Side effect: Your armor class decreases by {{mutation score}}.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <!-- <stat name="intelligence" value="mutation score" /> -->
            <!-- <stat name="intelligence:max" value="mutation score" /> -->
            <!-- <stat name="ac:misc" value="-mutation score" /> -->
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Shielded" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_SHIELDED">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain resistance to slashing damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> You gain vulnerability to bludgeoning damage.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain resistance to slashing damage. Side effect: You gain vulnerability to bludgeoning damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Unbreakable" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_UNBREAKABLE">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain resistance to bludgeoning damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> You gain vulnerability to piercing damage.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain resistance to bludgeoning damage. Side effect: You gain vulnerability to piercing damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Wariness" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_MUTAGEN_FORMULA_WARINESS">
        <supports>Mutagen Formula</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain a bonus to initiative equal to 2 times your mutation score.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Side effect:</i></b> You have disadvantage on intelligence (Perception) checks.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain a +{{wariness formula:initiative}} bonus to initiative. Side effect: You have disadvantage on intelligence (Perception) checks.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="wariness formula:initiative" value="mutation score" />
            <stat name="wariness formula:initiative" value="mutation score" />
        </rules>
    </element>
	<element name="Order of the Lycan" type="Archetype" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_BLOOD_HUNTER_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN">
        <supports>Blood Hunter Order</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Of the many terrible curses that plague the realm, few are as ancient or as feared Lycanthropy. Passed through blood, this affliction seeds a host with the savage strength and hunger for violence of a wild beast. Those that shun the curse spend their lives burying their wild, bestial urges deep inside. However, the power of a rising full moon makes the curse too strong to resist, and the host transforms into a terrifying animal-humanoid hybrid controlled by murderous impluse. Those that embrace the dark nature of their curse learn to harness their bestial gifts, but also succumb to the evil, vicious temperament that drives the beast within.</p>
            <p class="indent">The Order of the Lycan is a proud order of blood hunters who undergo “The Taming”, a ceremonial inflicting of lycanthrophy from a senior member. These hunters then use their abilities to harness the power of the moster they harbor without losing themselves to it. Through intense honing of one’s own willpower, combined with the secrets of the order’s blood magic rituals, members learn to control and unleash their hybrid form the short periods of time. Enhanced physical prowess, unnatural resilience, and razor sharp claws make these warriors a terrible foe to any evil that crosses their path. Yet, no training is perfect, and without care and complete focus, even the greatest of blood hunters can temporarily lose themselves to the bloodlust.</p>
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HEIGHTENED_SENSES" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_STALKERS_PROWESS" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_ADVANCED_TRANSFORMATION" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_IRON_VOLITION" />
            <div element="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_MASTERY" />
        </description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://www.dmsguild.com/product/175606/Order-of-the-Lycan-for-Blood-Hunters</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet display="false">
            <description>The process of consuming the Hunter’s Bane is a painful, scarring, and often fatal experience.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HEIGHTENED_SENSES" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION" level="3" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_STALKERS_PROWESS" level="7" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_ADVANCED_TRANSFORMATION" level="11" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_IRON_VOLITION" level="15" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_MASTERY" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Heightened Senses" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HEIGHTENED_SENSES">
        <description>
            <p>Starting when you choose this archetype at 3rd level, you begin to adopt to the improved abilities or a natural predator. You gain advantage on any Wisdom (Perception) checks that rely on hearing or smell.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain advantage on any Perception checks that rely on hearing or smell.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Hybrid Transformation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION">
        <description>
            <p>Upon choosing this archetype at 3rd level, you begin to learn to control the lycanthropic curse that now lives in your blood. As an action, you can transform into your Hybrid form. This form lasts for 10 minutes. You can speak, use equipment, and wear armor in this form. You can revert to your normal form earlier by using an action on your turn. You automatically revert to your normal form in you fall unconscious, drop to 0 hit points, or die. The benefits of this form replace the rules for Lucanthropy withing the Monster Manual.</p>
            <p class="indent">You can use this feature twice. You regain expended uses when you finish a short or long rest. While you are transformed, you gain the following features:</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Feral Might.</i></b> You gain a bonus to melee damage rolls equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down). You also have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.
            </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Resilient Hide.</i></b> You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons that aren’t silvered. While you are not wearing heavy armor, you gain a +1 bonus to your AC.
            </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Predatory Strikes.</i></b> Your unarmed strikes are considered a single weapon in regards to your crimson rite feature. You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes. When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strikem you can make another unarmed strike as a bonus action.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">Your unarmed strikes deal 1d6 slashing damage. This die increases to 1d8 at 11th level, and 1d10 at 18th level.</p>
            </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Bloodlust.</i></b> At the start of your turn, if you’ve taken any damage since the beginning of your last turn, you must make a Wisdom saving throw to maintain control. The DC equals 10, or half of the total damage you’ve taken from attacks since your last turn, whichever number is higher. On a failed save, you must move directly towards the nearest creature to you and use the Attack action against the creature. If there is more than one possible target, the DM chooses the target. You then regain control for the remainder of your turn.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">If you are under an effect that prevents you from concentrating (like the Barbarian’s rage feature), you automatically fail this saving throw.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action, you can transform into your Hybrid form. (2/SR)</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_FERAL_MIGHT" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_RESILIENT_HIDE" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_PREDATORY_STRIKES" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_CURSED_WEAKNESS" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_BLOODLUST" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Stalker’s Prowess" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_STALKERS_PROWESS">
        <description>
            <p>At 7th level, your speed increases by 10 feet. You also can add 10 feet to your long jump distance and 3 feet to your high jump distance.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, your hybrid form gains the Improved predatory Strikes feature.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Improved Predatory Strikes.</i></b> When you have an active rite while in your hybrid form, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Your speed increases by 10 feet. You can add 10 feet to your long jump distance and 3 feet to your high jump distance.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="speed" value="10" />
			<!-- todo: other speeds? -->
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_IMPROVED_PREDATORY_STRIKES" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Advanced Transformation" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_ADVANCED_TRANSFORMATION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 11th level, you learn to unleash and control more of the beast within. You can now transform into your hybrid form as a bonus action, and your hybrid transformation now lasts for up to 30 minutes.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, your hybrid form gains the Lycan Regeneration and Beastly Precision features.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Lycan Regeneration.</i></b>  At the start of each of your turns, you regain hit points equal to 1 + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1) if you have no more than half of your hit points left. You don’t gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points.
            </p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Beastly Precision.</i></b>  You gain a bonus to melee attack rolls made with your unarmed strikes equal to half of your proficiency bonus (rounded down).
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can now transform into your hybrid form as a bonus action, and your hybrid transformation now lasts for up to 30 minutes.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_LYCAN_REGENERATION" />
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_BEASTLY_PRECISION" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Iron Volition" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_IRON_VOLITION">
        <description>
            <p>Beginning at 15th level, you've honed your willpower to better resist the violent urges of your lycanthropic curse. Whenever you make a Wisdom saving throw to maintain control of your hybrid form, you do so with advantage.</p>
            <p class="indent">In addition, your hybrid form gains the Pack Hunter feature.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Pack Hunter.</i></b>  You have advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of your allies is withing 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>Whenever you make a Wisdom saving throw to maintain control of your hybrid form, you do so with advantage.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_PACK_HUNTER" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Hybrid Transformation Mastery" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_HYBRID_TRANSFORMATION_MASTERY">
        <description>
            <p>At 18th level, you have wrestled your inner predator and mastered it. You can now use your hybrid transformation feature three times between rests.</p>
            <p class="indent">You also gain the Blood Curse of the Howl for your blood malediction feature. This does not count against your blood curses known.</p>
            <p class="indent"><b><i>Blood Curse of the Howl.</i></b>  As an action, you howl at any number of creatures within 30 feet, chilling their blood and stunning them with fear. Any of the target creatures that can hear you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC equal to 8 + proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier) or become frightened of you until the end of your next turn instead. A creature that succeeds on this saving throw is immune to this blood curse for the next 24 hours.
            </p>
            <p class="indent">
                <i>Amplify.</i> This curse can target any number of creature within 60 feet of you.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You can now use your hybrid transformation feature three times between rests.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_THE_HOWL" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <!-- Hybrid Features -->
    <element name="Feral Might" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_FERAL_MIGHT">
        <supports>Hybrid Transformation Feature</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain a bonus to melee damage rolls equal to half your proficiency bonus (rounded down). You also have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain a +{{feral might:damage}} bonus to melee damage rolls. You also have advantage on Strength checks and Strength saving throws.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="feral might:damage" value="proficiency:half" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Resilient Hide" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_RESILIENT_HIDE">
        <supports>Hybrid Transformation Feature</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons that aren’t silvered. While you are not wearing heavy armor, you gain a +1 bonus to your AC.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have resistance to bludgeoning, piercing, and slashing damage from nonmagical weapons that aren’t silvered.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="ac:misc" value="1" equipped="![armor:heavy]" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Predatory Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_PREDATORY_STRIKES">
        <supports>Hybrid Transformation Feature</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Your unarmed strikes are considered a single weapon in regards to your crimson rite feature. You can use Dexterity instead of Strength for the attack and damage rolls of your unarmed strikes. When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strike you can make another unarmed strike as a bonus action.</p>
            <p class="indent">Your unarmed strikes deal 1d6 slashing damage. This die increases to 1d8 at 11th level, and 1d10 at 18th level.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you use the Attack action with an unarmed strike you can make another unarmed strike as a bonus action. (+{{predatory strikes:attack}} vs AC, 1d{{predatory strikes:damage}}+{{predatory strikes:attack:ability}})</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="predatory strikes:attack:ability" value="strength:modifier" bonus="ability" />
            <stat name="predatory strikes:attack:ability" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability" />
            <stat name="predatory strikes:attack" value="predatory strikes:attack:ability" />
            <stat name="predatory strikes:attack" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="predatory strikes:damage" value="6" />
            <stat name="predatory strikes:damage" value="8" level="11" />
            <stat name="predatory strikes:damage" value="10" level="18" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Bloodlust" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_BLOODLUST">
        <supports>Hybrid Transformation Feature</supports>
        <description>
            <p>At the start of your turn, if you’ve taken any damage since the beginning of your last turn, you must make a Wisdom saving throw to maintain control. The DC equals 10, or half of the total damage you’ve taken from attacks since your last turn, whichever number is higher. On a failed save, you must move directly towards the nearest creature to you and use the Attack action against the creature. If there is more than one possible target, the DM chooses the target. You then regain control for the remainder of your turn.</p>
            <p class="indent">If you are under an effect that prevents you from concentrating (like the Barbarian’s rage feature), you automatically fail this saving throw.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>At the start of your turn, if you’ve taken any damage since the beginning of your last turn, you must make a Wisdom saving throw to maintain control. The DC equals 10, or half of the total damage you’ve taken from attacks since your last turn, whichever number is higher. On a failed save, you must move directly towards the nearest creature to you and use the Attack action against the creature. You then regain control for the remainder of your turn.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Improved Predatory Strikes" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_IMPROVED_PREDATORY_STRIKES">
        <supports>Hybrid Transformation Feature</supports>
        <description>
            <p>When you have an active rite while in your hybrid form, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>When you have an active rite while in your hybrid form, your unarmed strikes are considered magical for the purpose of overcoming resistance and immunity to nonmagical attacks and damage.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Lycan Regeneration" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_LYCAN_REGENERATION">
        <supports>Hybrid Transformation Feature</supports>
        <description>
            <p>At the start of each of your turns, you regain hit points equal to 1 + your Constitution modifier (minimum of 1) if you have no more than half of your hit points left. You don’t gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>At the start of each of your turns, you regain {{lycan regeneration:hp}} hit points if you have no more than half of your hit points left. You don’t gain this benefit if you have 0 hit points.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="lycan regeneration:hp" value="1" />
            <stat name="lycan regeneration:hp" value="constitution:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
    <element name="Beastly Precision" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_BEASTLY_PRECISION">
        <supports>Hybrid Transformation Feature</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You gain a bonus to melee attack rolls made with your unarmed strikes equal to half of your proficiency bonus (rounded down).</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You gain a +{{proficiency:half}} bonus to melee attack rolls made with your unarmed strikes.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Pack Hunter" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_PACK_HUNTER">
        <supports>Hybrid Transformation Feature</supports>
        <description>
            <p>You have advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of your allies is withing 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You have advantage on an attack roll against a creature if at least one of your allies is withing 5 feet of the creature and the ally isn’t incapacitated.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    <element name="Blood Curse of the Howl" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role" id="ID_CRIT_ARCHETYPE_FEATURE_ORDER_OF_THE_LYCAN_BLOOD_CURSE_OF_THE_HOWL">
        <description>
            <p>As an action, you howl at any number of creatures within 30 feet, chilling their blood and stunning them with fear. Any of the target creatures that can hear you must succeed on a Wisdom saving throw (DC equal to 8 + proficiency bonus + your Wisdom modifier) or become frightened of you until the end of your next turn instead. A creature that succeeds on this saving throw is immune to this blood curse for the next 24 hours.</p>
            <p class="indent">
                <i>Amplify.</i> This curse can target any number of creature within 60 feet of you.
            </p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>As an action, you howl at any number of creatures within 30 feet. Any of the target creatures that can hear you must succeed on a DC{{blood curse howl:dc}} Wisdom saving throw or become frightened of you until the end of your next turn instead. Amplify: This curse can target any number of creature within 60 feet of you.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="blood curse howl:dc" value="8" />
            <stat name="blood curse howl:dc" value="proficiency" />
            <stat name="blood curse howl:dc" value="wisdom:modifier" />
        </rules>
    </element>
<!--end===========================================================================================================================-->
</elements>
